<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes &amp; Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</description>
    <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://seanzanganeh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 12:11:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 12:11:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Escrow Security Is Evolving</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ui7w_cOMtNc?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are joined by special guest Molly O’Dell of Oakwood Escrow, and we were so excited to have her join us. We talked about security, escrow, and what has changed in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email hacking is happening in every other industry and around the world, so why wouldn’t it happen in real estate? There is so much money going back and forth and these hackers are getting smart. &lt;strong&gt;They are watching the MLS, keeping an eye on pending transactions, then they hack the system and try to steal the buyer’s money via bogus wiring instructions.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve heard many horror stories about this kind of thing happening lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your escrow company isn’t savvy enough with their digital security, you could lose your money so easily as a buyer. Encrypted emails may be an extra step and a tad annoying, but it is really worth it. &lt;strong&gt;We have to encrypt our emails to make sure that our clients are safe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve seen too many buyers get scammed.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve seen too many buyers get scammed.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing that Molly thinks is important is to stop emailing wiring instructions. It’s commonly known that this is how hackers have stolen a lot of money in the past few years. At Oakwood Escrow, Molly and her team do not send wiring instructions via email. &lt;strong&gt;They can send them over the phone, via fax, or text message. It’s a lot safer than doing it over email.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the escrow process in the meantime, you can give Molly a call at (619) 889-5639 or send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(109,111,100,101,108,108,64,111,97,107,119,111,111,100,101,115,99,114,111,119,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;modell@oakwoodescrow.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate related questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering 3 Common Escrow Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s7rExJeuTM0?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of moving parts to every real estate transaction, and many people aren’t sure what happens during closing and escrow. Today, special guest Molly O’Dell from Oakwood Escrow is here to answer the three top escrow questions we get from our clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When is closing and what does that mean here in San Diego? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing date is based off the contract that the Realtor gives to the escrow company. Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days, although Molly says that it can be shorter or longer. At closing, all of the documents are signed and approved by all parties in the transaction: the lender, the title company, the buyer, and the seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. As a seller, when will the money from your home sale hit your bank account? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At closing, everything is sent to the title company within 24 hours, or the next business day. Your funds will probably hit your bank account the day after that, so you will get your money about 24 to 48 hours after closing the hold or file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Why do you have to sign documents with your Realtor and then sign documents with the escrow company? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your escrow company is a neutral third party. Although you signed contracts with your real estate agent allowing the escrow company to be part of the transaction, you still have to sign new documents with the escrow company. According to Molly, you don’t want your agent to sign your escrow documents because the escrow company is supposed to be a completely neutral third party. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An independent escrow company is very important to both buyers and sellers. An independent escrow company doesn’t have a hand in the buyer agent’s commission or the listing agent’s commission. There are some in-house escrow companies that are affiliated with real estate agents. If they are under the same roof and same name as a real estate agent, they will obviously have a preferred party in each transaction. Molly says that the value of an independent escrow company is that they are able to step back and help both sides equally. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for Molly, you can reach her at modell@oakwoodescrow.com or (619) 889-5639. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Will the Rise in Loan Limits This Year Impact the Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bQy9enNjUFY?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I have with me special guest Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage, the man of all things mortgage. He’ll be discussing the rise in loan limits this year and how that can help you win in the San Diego real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Todd, the situation incredible—this is the biggest rise in loan limits that we’ve seen in a couple years. Conforming loan limits are up to $453,100 for single-family residents in San Diego. On high balance loan limits, we went up to $679,650.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unbelievable because &lt;strong&gt;it means that when you’re looking at something in the $800,000 range and putting down 20%, you’ve got a great opportunity to get conforming interest rates.&lt;/strong&gt; In the past, you’d have to go through the jumbo loan process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also pertains to multi-units. Todd sees a lot of clients who own triplexes and were limited on how much cash they could pull out of those properties who can now pull cash out at much higher numbers than they could last year. &lt;strong&gt;Now they’re able to use that to buy more properties or pay down their mortgage on their personal residences&lt;/strong&gt;. They can take advantage of both sides of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our end, with the mid-range, detached home prices in the mid-$700,000 price point in San Diego, being able to have this high loan balance lowers the amount that people are required to put down on a higher-priced home. &lt;strong&gt;People are able to get the home they want in the time they want at the rate that makes sense for them&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is the biggest rise in loan limits that we’ve seen in a couple years.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-will-the-rise-in-loan-limits-this-year-impact-the-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is the biggest rise in loan limits that we’ve seen in a couple years.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another cool aspect, according to Todd, is that these new limits also pertain to VA and FHA loans. It means that you have a 3.5%-down FHA program where you can basically buy a mid-range, detached home and get an incredible interest rate. With the VA loan, you can put 0% down. &lt;strong&gt;This could actually stimulate the market&lt;/strong&gt;rather than hurt it, as people are concerned about with the recent tax reform. It will help both first-time and experienced homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are really excited to be able to help families in 2018. If he can be of help to you, Todd can be reached at (858) 775-8958 or tpianin@rpm-mtg.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todd Pianin, Regional Manager NMLS# 304014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LendUS, LLC dba RPM Mortgage NMLS #1938 - Licensed by the Department of Business Oversight under the CA Residential Mortgage Lending Act. Equal Housing Opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need any tips and tricks on how to win in the San Diego real estate market, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help you out this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-will-the-rise-in-loan-limits-this-year-impact-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-will-the-rise-in-loan-limits-this-year-impact-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Important Mortgage Information for Millennial Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DJLglgcV7bY?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m happy to be joined by a special guest, Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage, to have a discussion about millennial homebuyers in the San Diego market. Todd has some awesome lending tips that will help any millennial who is looking to buy their first home become competitive in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many millennials grew up during the 2007 credit crisis.&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, a lot of them only deal with cash and don’t have credit cards. If you’re a millennial that doesn’t have a credit card but wants to buy a house, you should know that you’ll need to have at least three different cards in order to purchase one. It’s important that you start building your credit now, especially if homeownership is in your future plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One other big problem we’ve run into with millennials is a lack of rental history.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re in a situation where you’re living with a friend and renting a room from them, you should ask to get added to the lease. If you’ve been out of college for a few years and don’t have any rental history, it’s pretty hard to get qualified for a mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Start building your credit now.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/important-mortgage-information-for-millennial-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Start building your credit now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do have all of your ducks in a row, it gives you a huge advantage in the marketplace. Inventory is so tight now in San Diego and there’s talk of even less inventory in the future. &lt;strong&gt;By having good credit and a solid rental history, Todd and his team can issue you an advanced approval in order to get your fully approved &lt;/strong&gt;(subject to appraisal, escrow, and title). This will allow you to close on a home in just 14 days, which is much quicker than the average buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to start the pre-approval process or you just have any questions about credit or mortgages in general, give Todd a call at (858) 775-8958 or send an email over to Tpianin@rpm-mtg.com. If you have any other questions for us about the San Diego real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out anytime. We look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/important-mortgage-information-for-millennial-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/important-mortgage-information-for-millennial-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Prevent a Home Sale From Falling Apart</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nwxy8ydstaY?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself in the process of buying or selling a home only for something to go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether this has ever happened to you or not, I would like to share some tips today on how to prevent a real estate transaction from falling apart. During any transaction, there are three main hurdles. Let’s take a look at what they are and how to overcome them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes, this is the point where a buyer may find something they dislike about the home and simply walk away. The issue they find may not even be all that significant. Still, it can be confusing to a seller to have this happen, especially if their home was receiving multiple offers. For this reason, I recommend that sellers get rid of as many of these small issues as they can ahead of time. Anything you can fix for under $100 could make a big difference. During a real estate transaction, preparation such as this is key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appraisals.&lt;/strong&gt; Problems related to appraisals typically come up due to lack of preparation. To help combat that, my team and I like to accompany our client in meeting the appraiser on the property when entering escrow. The appraiser probably doesn’t know the neighborhood of the home as well as our client or we might. This additional step can really demonstrate the value of the property so that the home is more likely to appraise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The loan.&lt;/strong&gt; Too many buyers out there aren’t truly pre-approved. When we have a buyer open escrow with us on our listings, we cross-qualify them with our lender just to be sure. This prevents people from spending a lot of money on a transaction only to realize they aren’t qualified to buy a home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=During a real estate transaction, preparation is key.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-prevent-a-home-sale-from-falling-apart.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“During a real estate transaction, preparation is key.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-prevent-a-home-sale-from-falling-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-prevent-a-home-sale-from-falling-apart.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is It Possible to Find the Right Home During Our Current Inventory Crisis?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0GT-jravLo0?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you struggling to find a home here in San Diego County? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Diego is in an inventory crisis right now. There are simply more buyers than there are available homes. So when a property does get listed, it receives a lot of attention. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ve got three tips and tricks for helping you win out in our local real estate market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Work with an active agent or team.&lt;/strong&gt; Who you work with really does matter. You need to be working with a busy agent or team who is in touch with the current market. My team and I are always dedicated to searching out and following up on deals. When you work with us, we can offer you valuable inside knowledge on how to secure a property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Find an agent that is constantly working to find new properties.&lt;/strong&gt; Professionals who keep a constant eye on the market are going to help you immensely when it comes to finding the right home. Your chances will be even better if an agent can bring you a property that few people know about yet. The less competition a home sees, the better your chances are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make sure you find out about off-market properties.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t forget to check out properties that were listed a few years ago and have been recently relisted. These homes could present you with some unique opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The less competition a listing sees, the better your chances are.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/is-it-possible-to-find-the-right-home-during-our-current-inventory-crisis.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The less competition a listing sees, the better your chances are.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/is-it-possible-to-find-the-right-home-during-our-current-inventory-crisis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/is-it-possible-to-find-the-right-home-during-our-current-inventory-crisis.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons Why the Holiday Season Is a Great Time to Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HXNYZOSNgv0?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five reasons why the holiday season is a great time to sell your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. People who look for homes during this time are serious buyers&lt;/strong&gt;. They’re looking to close before the end of the year or the early part of January. If there are fewer homes on the market and you’re looking at the competition, you have to make a decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The supply of homes decreases&lt;/strong&gt;. Fewer and fewer homes come on the market toward the end of the year because people who tested the market earlier in the year usually decide to pull their homes off the MLS and wait until next year. That leaves only serious sellers looking to make a deal and move before the end of the year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. People may need to move for tax and timing reasons&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of folks may be 1031-ing out of a particular property or need to close before the end of the year for tax reasons. These people are likely to make a decision, close fast, and make it easy for you as a seller to move or potentially rent back until the beginning of next year so it doesn’t interrupt your holiday schedule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. By selling your home now, you can become a non-contingent buyer in the spring&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Your home shows better during the holidays&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll likely have friends and family visiting you sometime, so you’ll probably do a little extra cleaning and decorating anyway to make sure your home is spic and span. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers are far more serious this time of year.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/5-reasons-why-the-holiday-season-is-a-great-time-to-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers are far more serious this time of year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about selling your home in the fall or you’re curious about our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to get together and chat with you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/5-reasons-why-the-holiday-season-is-a-great-time-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/5-reasons-why-the-holiday-season-is-a-great-time-to-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Owning a Second Home in San Diego</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0700yYasVi4?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put together some tips and tricks regarding buying a second home in San Diego, specifically some tax considerations you should talk over with your CPA if you’re thinking about buying a second home in the San Diego area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage interest deduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Here in San Diego, you can write off the mortgage interest on your property for up to a million dollars. That can get you a great place near the beach, downtown, up in Carlsbad, or a ranch property somewhere in San Diego.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing off your property taxes&lt;/strong&gt;: You can write off all your property taxes without a limit. There is a caveat, however. If your annual income puts you in a tax bracket over $311,000, there are limits to how much you can write off, so make sure you talk with your CPA about how much of a write off you are allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renting out your second property&lt;/strong&gt;: Did you know you can rent out your San Diego property for up to 14 days and not pay any taxes on that income? That means your second property can become a source of tax-free income over holiday weekends like the Fourth of July, or over winter break when a lot the snowbirds are coming down to San Diego to catch some sunshine. It is possible to rent out your second property and have two or three months worth of your annual mortgage covered by the tax-free income from that 14 days of rental. It is important to remember that renting beyond 14 days a year makes that income taxable and can change the status of your second property to a rental property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can shift your primary residence&lt;/strong&gt;: When it comes time to sell, you may consider making your second home in San Diego your primary residence. In doing so, a married couple can avoid paying up to $500,000 in capital-gains taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is possible to rent out your second property and have two to three months worth of your annual mortgage covered by the tax-free income from that 14 days of rental.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/owning-a-second-home-in-san-diego.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is possible to rent out your second property and have two to three months worth of your annual mortgage covered by the tax-free income from that 14 days of rental.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering making that purchase of a second home here in San Diego, these are some subjects that could save you a lot of money and that you should definitely talk to a CPA about. If you’d like to talk to me or have any questions, feel free to contact me at (858) 229-6063 or online at sean@mysddreamhome.com. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/owning-a-second-home-in-san-diego.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/owning-a-second-home-in-san-diego.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Overlook These Critical Property Features</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4N9zCGqJr48?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to think about whenever you’re taking steps to purchase your next home. Of course, one of the first things to do is to sync up with a great real estate agent who’s really got your back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even so, there are a couple of things you shouldn’t overlook in your transaction. Even with the help of an agent, you want to pay close attention to certain aspects, yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, pay attention to the neighborhood. Typically speaking, you’ll visit properties with your real estate agent around a pretty consistent time of day. My team and I personally recommend revisiting any property you’re interested in at different times, to get a true feel for the community and know exactly what you’re getting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, ask yourself what your commute will be like. &lt;strong&gt;Your lifestyle should be a key consideration in your decision on whether to buy a certain home.&lt;/strong&gt;Whether you want to be close to work, to school, to family, or to a lot of restaurants, it’s important to know how far you’re going to need to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, be sure to look into the rules of the community. A lot of communities in our area have homeowners associations or CC&amp;amp;Rs (Covenants, Conditions, and Restrictions) that may impact things like the colors you can paint your home, what you can park in front of your house, and what kinds of pets are allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure a property matches your long-term goals.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/dont-overlook-these-critical-property-features.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure a property matches your long-term goals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing people sometimes forget is to critically consider the bedroom-to-bathroom ratio. &lt;strong&gt;Think realistically about how much space you and your family are going to need.&lt;/strong&gt;Even something that may work for you now may not work in the future if you plan on growing your family. Before deciding on a home, really think about what makes sense for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also make sure to change your HVAC systems. A lot of property in San Diego has septic systems, solar systems, wells, and other features. Look into what maintenance is going to cost you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another question to ask yourself is if you’re okay with features that can’t be changed. &lt;strong&gt;Things like location, lot size, and the floor plan are all features you’re going to have to live with for however long you stay.&lt;/strong&gt;Make sure you’re happy with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also think about your resale value. You need to have a clear understanding of what it costs to own the home, what the home’s potential value is, and what rents are going for in the neighborhood in case you ever decide to rent the property out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, decide if a given property will realistically be sufficient for you and your family’s growth in a long-term sense. Depending on how long you want to stay on a property, you really need to think about this factor. &lt;strong&gt;My team and I often see people try to squeeze into a home that is too small, simply because it fits their budget.&lt;/strong&gt;Don’t make this same mistake. Make sure a property matches your long-term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/dont-overlook-these-critical-property-features.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/dont-overlook-these-critical-property-features.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Home Repairs You Can’t Afford to Ignore</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBNDBPVLJ1A?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back with some more tips and tricks to help you win in the San Diego real estate market. Whether you’re thinking of selling your home soon or just looking to increase its value, there are a number of home repairs that you definitely should not put off when they are needed. Here are nine of them to keep an eye on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Caulking around areas where there may be exposed water.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes bathrooms, kitchens, windows, and anywhere else where water can penetrate. We had a home on the market that didn’t pay attention to this and it ended up costing the owners $10,000 to fix the kitchen when it flooded. It’s much easier to buy a $10 caulking gun at the hardware store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Cleaning your dryer vent.&lt;/strong&gt; So many people forget to do this. You should have it cleaned at least once a year to prevent a fire hazard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Roof repairs.&lt;/strong&gt; With sun and water constantly hitting our roofs in San Diego, they can get eaten up pretty quickly. Any time you find a roof leak or imperfection, call a roofer. It’s better to spend a few hundred now than a few thousand later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Chimney sweep.&lt;/strong&gt; For a few hundred bucks, there are plenty of companies out there that will come out and do a full sweep of all your chimneys to further reduce fire hazards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Change your HVAC filters.&lt;/strong&gt; When people don’t change their filters for months or even years, they get clogged and bog down the system. That can cause it to burn out. Get these filters changed often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Pest problems.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s termites, rodents, or other pests, you want to handle any pest problems very early on. It can get very expensive if you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Fix any plumbing leaks as soon as you find them.&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of the more costly repairs that we see. A simple leaky pipe can cause major damage if not handled properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Peeling paint.&lt;/strong&gt; If you see any chipped, cracked, or peeling paint, throw a fresh coat on top. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Drainage problems.&lt;/strong&gt; We see this a lot in homes with plants or sprinklers near the house. The stucco next to the house tends to get eaten away quite quickly. If that’s the case for you, it’s time to change to a drip system to make your home ready for the next time we get a big winter rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Pests need to be dealt with immediately.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/9-home-repairs-you-cant-afford-to-ignore.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Pests need to be dealt with immediately.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few things that you should stay on top of as a homeowner, whether you’re thinking of selling soon or not. If you are and you need any assistance from us, we’d be happy to help. Just give us a call or send us an email today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/9-home-repairs-you-cant-afford-to-ignore.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/9-home-repairs-you-cant-afford-to-ignore.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
