<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes &amp; Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</description>
    <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://seanzanganeh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 14:57:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 14:57:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Propositions 60 and 90 Can Help You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6p38nVFL9vU?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you heard about &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Propositions 60 and 90&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;? If you&amp;rsquo;re 55 or older, you need to know about how they can help you save on your taxes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you 55 or older and want to keep your tax bases? &lt;strong&gt;If so, we’ve got some great information for you today&lt;/strong&gt;. Our lovely guests, Shawn and Alix from Fidelity Title, are joining us to talk about Propositions 60 and 90 and why they’re important to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Propositions 60 and 90 are constitutional amendments in California that allow tax relief for a homeowner who is 55 years of age or older&lt;/strong&gt;. This allows them to transfer that tax base to another property. There are some requirements you need to meet in order to qualify for these. Here are the most important:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Either you or your spouse has to be 55 or older.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The home has to be your principal residence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you’re making the transfer, it has to be to a property that is of equal or lower market value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You must find the replacement property within two years of selling your current home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There could be some interesting changes coming to this amendment.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-propositions-60-and-90-can-help-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There could be some interesting changes coming to this amendment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are some potential upgrades coming to Propositions 60 and 90 as well&lt;/strong&gt;. They aren’t on the ballot in California yet, but signatures are being collected right now. If these amendments pass, they open up the benefits to all of San Diego County and will allow homeowners to use them more than once. Currently, you can only transfer the tax base once. Another big change could allow you to transfer your tax base to a home that’s worth more instead of being at equal or lesser value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something like this happens in the near future, that would open up the market to a ton of buyers in the area. If you want more information about how you can qualify for Propositions 60 and 90, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you and talk to you more about how you can benefit from the San Diego real estate market right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-propositions-60-and-90-can-help-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-propositions-60-and-90-can-help-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Insure Your Condominiums</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9-HnZzfIUeo?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you confused about what type of condominium insurance you should purchase?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in buying a condo but have no idea how to insure it? Condos are insured differently than homes and there are multiple ways we see them show up. Today Seth Arruda of Alta Vista Insurance Agency and I will look at the top three ways we see condos insured as well as the types of insurance that clients get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways that a homeowners association (HOA) will insure a condo. The most common way is to &lt;strong&gt;provide coverage of the exterior of the buildings and the common areas&lt;/strong&gt;. That leaves the owner of the specific condo to insure the inside of the unit. This is called a unit owner’s policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seth tells us that he has also seen situations where the HOA will &lt;strong&gt;only provide coverage for their common areas&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that you will own your roof, your side, your exterior, and your interior, but you are within a smaller subdivision where there are smaller homes on zero lot lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final way that an HOA can insure a condominium is by &lt;strong&gt;providing coverage for the common area and the structures, leaving everything behind the walls in each unit as the responsibility of the unit owner&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that items such as plumbing lines, service lines, and electrical lines all need to be insured under your unit owner’s policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Try to obtain a copy of your CC&amp;amp;Rs and review the contract with your insurance agent.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-insure-your-condominiums.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Try to obtain a copy of your CC&amp;amp;Rs and review the contract with your insurance agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each type of policy is very specific and it is very important to find out what is covered in each situation. If you own or are looking to purchase a condominium, you should try to obtain a copy of your Covenants, Conditions, &amp;amp; Restrictions (CC&amp;amp;Rs) and review the contract with your insurance agent to ensure your unit is properly protected and that you have the right coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seth is our contact when it comes to finding insurance in San Diego and has helped us for a long time. If you are looking for a great broker to help you navigate your situation, you can call Seth at (760) 724-2124.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always if you are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-insure-your-condominiums.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-insure-your-condominiums.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Insurance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Convert Covered Patios Into Additional Living Space</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zq1q6Yoot6w?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can you convert a covered patio into additional living space? Today we&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing this topic with a local expert.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a patio or outdoor area that you want to convert into an additional living space? If so, we’ve got a few tips and tricks for how you can do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining us to help cover this topic is Ian Scattergood of Permit Pro Consultants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can someone go about adding additional space to their home with an enclosed patio? According to Ian, the first thing to consider is whether the space meets the floor area ratio (or FAR) and the lot coverage. &lt;strong&gt;Once this is confirmed, plans can be drawn, the permit can be issued, and the homeowner can proceed with converting the space&lt;/strong&gt; into additional square footage or a second rentable unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to realize, though, that the process varies when it comes to older structures. What then must be done to ensure older structures can qualify as additional living space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Qualifying older structures as additional living space mostly comes down to meeting specific city or county zone ordinances.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-convert-covered-patios-into-additional-living-space.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Qualifying older structures as additional living space mostly comes down to meeting specific city or county zone ordinances.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian says it mostly comes down to meeting specific city or county zone ordinances. &lt;strong&gt;If everything checks out under those ordinances, then the same process as before can be carried out&lt;/strong&gt; to qualify the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to call Ian at (619) 579-0088 or email him at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as always, if you have any questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ian Scattergood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Permit Pro Consultants&lt;br /&gt;(619) 579-0088&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-convert-covered-patios-into-additional-living-space.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-to-convert-covered-patios-into-additional-living-space.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Really Know Who Owns the Property?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xD5k78LANCQ?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The issue of ownership is very important when it comes time to list a home. Today we will discuss a few key scenarios about listing after ownership-related complications arise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you considering selling your home but don’t really know who owns the house? Well today I am joined by Shawn Harris and Alix Kammeyer from Fidelity National Title to discuss this important real estate quandary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often meet with a seller only to find that they are not the person listed on the title. If this situation arises, &lt;strong&gt;the first important thing to know is how a property is vested&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the following scenario: A husband and wife named Robert and Susan are on the title as joint tenants on a property. Now Susan has passed away and Robert is attempting to list the property, but he has not done anything to indicate his wife’s passing on the title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this situation, Robert can still proceed with listing, but he will need to provide a valid copy of Susan’s death certificate and sign an affidavit of death of joint tenants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what about when a family owns a home in a trust?&lt;/strong&gt; How does this impact a person’s ability to list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To explain this, let’s return to the scenario we mentioned earlier. In this version of our example, Robert and Susan are still a married couple, Susan has passed away, and their property is owned in a trust. Before Robert can list, the title company will need to see the trust and verify that Susan was one of the trustees and that Robert is the only other trustee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot goes into listing a home, especially if ownership issues are at play.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/do-you-really-know-who-owns-the-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot goes into listing a home, especially if ownership issues are at play.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, the process will proceed in the same way as we previously described. Robert will still need to provide the two documents mentioned earlier, but, other than that, he would be able to proceed with listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;how can ownership of a property be impacted as a result of a divorce?&lt;/strong&gt; In the state of California, 50% of marriages do not work out. So, this question is sure to be on the minds of many as they prepare to list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of ways this scenario can unfold. Let’s use our imaginary couple, Robert and Susan, to explain once more. This time, imagine that Robert and Susan have been divorced for five or six years. Susan has quitclaimed her interest off because Robert was awarded the property, and she is now living in Europe. If Robert has not refinanced the home or had title insurance issued, he will need to acquire an affidavit of uninsured deed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be very difficult to obtain, so the first step before this comes into play is to look at the marriage settlement agreement and verify that Robert was truly awarded the property. Once this is verified, another important point to check is that Susan didn’t sign the quitclaim under duress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is apparent, a lot goes into listing a home, especially if ownership issues are at play. It is critical to &lt;strong&gt;get in touch with a title company before proceeding with your sale to make sure everything goes smoothly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for more information and want to get in touch with Shawn or Alix, you can contact them with the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shawn Harris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;shawn@mytitleandescrow.com&lt;br /&gt;(760) 271-8584&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alix Kammeyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;alix@mytitleandescrow.com&lt;br /&gt;(619) 933-9621&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/do-you-really-know-who-owns-the-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/do-you-really-know-who-owns-the-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering All Your Questions About Insurance</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PREFgaP5bYI?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seth Arruda of Alta Vista Insurance joins me to talk about insurance options to consider when purchasing a home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am joined by Seth Arruda to talk to you about looking for insurance in the middle of a real estate transaction. I have some tips and tricks which should help you win in the San Diego market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what things must a consumer know to make an educated choice about insurance coverage? Let’s take a look at the five questions consumers should ask themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What is covered?&lt;br /&gt;2. How much coverage do you need?&lt;br /&gt;3. How do you insure your personal property and belongings?&lt;br /&gt;4. How do you insure the items which mean the most?&lt;br /&gt;5. What about liability?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, what is covered? In California, standard hazard or fire insurance, as everyone likes to call it, insures you for sudden, accidental occurrences and catastrophic perils such as fire, wind, hail, and lightning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much coverage does a client need on a house?&lt;/strong&gt; This is where we get into talking about replacement cost value of a home. Insurance companies insure the structures based on their reconstruction costs, so they are not concerned with the market value of a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In California, standard hazard insurance insures you for sudden, accidental occurrences and catastrophic perils such as fire, wind, hail, and lightning.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-all-your-questions-about-insurance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In California, standard hazard insurance insures you for sudden, accidental occurrences and catastrophic perils such as fire, wind, hail, and lightning.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about insuring personal belongings?&lt;/strong&gt; You need to make sure that you carry replacement cost value for all the contents in your home. With this insurance, if any of your personal items are destroyed due to a covered peril, you will get the full replacement for those items such as furniture, electronics, clothing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I cover my expensive jewelry, diamonds, gold, collectibles, and antiques?&lt;/strong&gt; The insurance companies call those items “scheduled personal property,” and you want to make sure that they are itemized on your insurance policy. You will usually need an appraisal or receipt showing the value of the items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;what do we cover with liability?&lt;/strong&gt; Liability is attached to your home insurance and will give you liability protection for your residence premises and personal injury matters. You want to have proper liability for things such as libel or slander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there is a lot that goes into insurance, which is why you should have a good insurance broker that can shop several different options. You can contact Seth at (760) 724-2124 if you would like to speak to him about a new policy or modifying your existing policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Arruda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alta Vista Insurance&lt;br /&gt;(760) 724-2124&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altavistainsurance.com/&quot;&gt;altavistainsurance.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-all-your-questions-about-insurance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-all-your-questions-about-insurance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <category>Insurance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Here's How to Build a Granny Flat in San Diego</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0quoEEj-QaY?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you thinking about building an ADU or granny flat on your property? Today I have Ian Scattergood with me to talk about the guidelines for San Diego.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you looking to build a granny flat or accessory unit on your property? Today we have Ian Scattergood, a permit pro, with us to discuss how to get a granny flat or accessory dwelling unit built (ADU) on your property in San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has become a very popular topic in San Diego for many reasons. Some people want to rent out space for income on Airbnb or VRBO, while others simply want their guests to have a place to stay during their visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An accessory dwelling unit (ADU) is a second rentable unit on a single-family developed lot&lt;/strong&gt;. There are some basic rules in San Diego for those people who want to build an ADU. &lt;strong&gt;The state requires a minimum size of 150 square feet and a maximum of 1,200 square feet&lt;/strong&gt;. It must also have bathing facilities and cooking facilities, which can be a ¾ bath and a kitchenette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each jurisdiction can have either more restrictive or less restrictive guidelines than the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Each jurisdiction can have either more restrictive or less restrictive guidelines than what the state has.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/heres-how-to-build-a-granny-flat-in-san-diego.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Each jurisdiction can have either more restrictive or less restrictive guidelines than what the state has.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, you can call Ian’s office and provide the address at which you are considering building the ADU. He will Google the location to decide if it is a prime candidate to move forward and then contact you about what he thinks. Based on your jurisdiction, &lt;strong&gt;he can provide the guidelines and can help you decide if you want to consider building&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people in San Diego may want to convert a current space, such as another garage or craft room, into a livable space. &lt;strong&gt;You can take an old garage, shed, or legally permitted granny flat and convert it into a unit&lt;/strong&gt; as long as it abides by new fire &amp;amp; life safety codes. A new law provides relaxed setbacks and off-street parking guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contact Ian for more information about if your property qualifies at (619) 579-0088.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about the real estate market here in San Diego, please don’t hesitate to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ian Scattergood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Permit Pro Consultants&lt;br /&gt;(619) 579-0088&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/heres-how-to-build-a-granny-flat-in-san-diego.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/heres-how-to-build-a-granny-flat-in-san-diego.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should Homebuyers Know About Looking Over the Title Report?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aZ1siMOSYHc?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking over the title report as a buyer is an important step in real estate process. Today I&amp;rsquo;ve brought on two experts to explain why this is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve made an offer on a home, gotten accepted, and received a copy of the title report. Now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Shawn and Alex from Fidelity Title to talk about a common question: &lt;strong&gt;What do you do with a title report once you’re in escrow?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buyers, looking at the preliminary title report will be very important. This title report will alert you to things such as easements and CC&amp;amp;Rs. First of all, many of you may be wondering: “What’s a CC&amp;amp;R, and why should I care?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great question. &lt;strong&gt;CC&amp;amp;R stands for covenants, codes, and restrictions. Basically, CC&amp;amp;Rs are standards that govern what you can and cannot do to a property&lt;/strong&gt;. If you wanted to paint your home pink, for example, you would look to your home’s CC&amp;amp;Rs to see if doing so would be allowed. CC&amp;amp;Rs for condos might even dictate the size, weight, and number of pets you can have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These standards sound similar to what you might find with an HOA, but many homes outside of any HOA still come with CC&amp;amp;Rs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=For buyers, looking at the preliminary title report will be very important.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/what-should-homebuyers-know-about-looking-over-the-title-report.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“For buyers, looking at the preliminary title report will be very important.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special programs are another thing that can appear on title reports&lt;/strong&gt;. Homes with solar panels present one common example of when these programs come into play. Solar panels can be leased or purchased. Leased solar panels may fall within the Purchase Power Program or the Hero Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Hero Program, the tax bill will show the amount owed on a yearly basis. When you examine this tax bill as a buyer, you want to ensure that this is listed as a line item on the exception. However, if you don’t see it on the tax bill, it doesn’t mean the program doesn’t exist. It all depends on when the seller got the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do business with my team and I, Shawn and Alex go through every single title report to make sure there’s nothing wrong. We’re truly lucky to have their help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for more information and want to get in touch with Shawn or Alix, you can contact them with the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shawn Harris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;shawn@mytitleandescrow.com&lt;br /&gt;(760) 271-8584&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alix Kammeyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;alix@mytitleandescrow.com&lt;br /&gt;(619) 933-9621&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always, if you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/what-should-homebuyers-know-about-looking-over-the-title-report.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/what-should-homebuyers-know-about-looking-over-the-title-report.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Hot Lending Topics for 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/itB0wkyDcNI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s going on in the lending world right now in San Diego? There are three main topics I&amp;rsquo;d like to go over, today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m joined today by special guest Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage to talk about a few hot topics relating to mortgage lending and real estate in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re focusing on three subjects, specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax reform&lt;/strong&gt;. Right now, tax reform is a huge topic in San Diego. With property tax deductions capped at $10,000 and mortgage interest deductions capped at $750,000, many people are concerned. As a result, Todd tells me that he’s been receiving a lot of calls about refinancing. Still, Todd doesn’t believe tax reform will slow down the market. He says people still need to buy homes, so they shouldn’t let these changes prevent them from doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paying points&lt;/strong&gt;. Todd says people need to start talking about paying points, since points are still tax deductible. If you’re paying points, you can actually buy down your interest rate to eventually earn a better one. You can also deduct points on a refinance, as well, if you deduct over the lifetime of the loan. A lot of mortgage lenders are scared to sell points because they aren’t used to doing so, but Todd has been doing this for the last 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niche programs&lt;/strong&gt;. According to Todd, 2018 will be the “year of the niche.” There are already a number of diverse programs available in today’s market. Whatever a buyer’s circumstances may be, there is likely a program out there to suit their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People still need to buy homes, so they shouldn’t let tax reform prevent them from doing so.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/3-hot-lending-topics-for-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People still need to buy homes, so they shouldn’t let tax reform prevent them from doing so.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for more mortgage information and want to get in touch with Todd, you can give him a call at (858) 775-8958 or email him at tpianin@rpm-mtg.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todd Pianin, Regional Manager NMLS# 304014&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;LendUS, LLC dba RPM Mortgage NMLS #1938 - Licensed by the Department of Business Oversight under the CA Residential Mortgage Lending Act. Equal Housing Opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always, if you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/3-hot-lending-topics-for-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/3-hot-lending-topics-for-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Taxes</category>
        
        <category>Tax Reform</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Escrow Security Is Evolving</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ui7w_cOMtNc?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are joined by special guest Molly O’Dell of Oakwood Escrow, and we were so excited to have her join us. We talked about security, escrow, and what has changed in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email hacking is happening in every other industry and around the world, so why wouldn’t it happen in real estate? There is so much money going back and forth and these hackers are getting smart. &lt;strong&gt;They are watching the MLS, keeping an eye on pending transactions, then they hack the system and try to steal the buyer’s money via bogus wiring instructions.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve heard many horror stories about this kind of thing happening lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your escrow company isn’t savvy enough with their digital security, you could lose your money so easily as a buyer. Encrypted emails may be an extra step and a tad annoying, but it is really worth it. &lt;strong&gt;We have to encrypt our emails to make sure that our clients are safe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve seen too many buyers get scammed.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve seen too many buyers get scammed.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing that Molly thinks is important is to stop emailing wiring instructions. It’s commonly known that this is how hackers have stolen a lot of money in the past few years. At Oakwood Escrow, Molly and her team do not send wiring instructions via email. &lt;strong&gt;They can send them over the phone, via fax, or text message. It’s a lot safer than doing it over email.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the escrow process in the meantime, you can give Molly a call at (619) 889-5639 or send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(109,111,100,101,108,108,64,111,97,107,119,111,111,100,101,115,99,114,111,119,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;modell@oakwoodescrow.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate related questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering 3 Common Escrow Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s7rExJeuTM0?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of moving parts to every real estate transaction, and many people aren’t sure what happens during closing and escrow. Today, special guest Molly O’Dell from Oakwood Escrow is here to answer the three top escrow questions we get from our clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When is closing and what does that mean here in San Diego? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing date is based off the contract that the Realtor gives to the escrow company. Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days, although Molly says that it can be shorter or longer. At closing, all of the documents are signed and approved by all parties in the transaction: the lender, the title company, the buyer, and the seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days.%20http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. As a seller, when will the money from your home sale hit your bank account? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At closing, everything is sent to the title company within 24 hours, or the next business day. Your funds will probably hit your bank account the day after that, so you will get your money about 24 to 48 hours after closing the hold or file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Why do you have to sign documents with your Realtor and then sign documents with the escrow company? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your escrow company is a neutral third party. Although you signed contracts with your real estate agent allowing the escrow company to be part of the transaction, you still have to sign new documents with the escrow company. According to Molly, you don’t want your agent to sign your escrow documents because the escrow company is supposed to be a completely neutral third party. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An independent escrow company is very important to both buyers and sellers. An independent escrow company doesn’t have a hand in the buyer agent’s commission or the listing agent’s commission. There are some in-house escrow companies that are affiliated with real estate agents. If they are under the same roof and same name as a real estate agent, they will obviously have a preferred party in each transaction. Molly says that the value of an independent escrow company is that they are able to step back and help both sides equally. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for Molly, you can reach her at modell@oakwoodescrow.com or (619) 889-5639. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanzanganeh.com/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
