<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes &amp; Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 11:43:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 11:43:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways Young People Can Build Wealth Through Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2IxIwrwHGAg?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are three ways to build your real estate portfolio in San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many first-time homebuyers are looking to purchase homes, but they’re finding that prices are just too high for them. I’d both agree and disagree with their assessments; it all depends on what you’re looking at. Today I’ll share three great ways to help you build your portfolio and wealth here in San Diego:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Condos.&lt;/strong&gt; In today’s market, condos are probably the most underrated asset class. Over the last 12 to 18 months, so many people have shifted their focus to single-family homes that the condo market has softened and people are getting deals. Post pandemic, we’ll likely see the condo market come back strong as people use them for second homes and other purposes. I’ve seen a ton of clients gain lots of equity from condos, and it’s substantially easier to get into that market than the detached housing market these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many young people don’t think of real estate as a great partnership opportunity, but it can be.%20http://localhost:4000/3-ways-young-people-can-build-wealth-through-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many young people don’t think of real estate as a great partnership opportunity, but it can be.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. “House hack” by renting out bought property.&lt;/strong&gt; House hacking is where you purchase a large or multi-unit property and rent it out to tenants. The rent you receive can offset the cost of the property. Suppose you had a two-unit property in a desirable location where you couldn’t normally qualify for two units at $750,000. By purchasing a two-unit property there, you can use the rent generated to offset the property’s expenses, so it might feel like you’re only buying a $500,000 property. This is useful for those who want to live with another person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Buy real estate with someone.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re looking to start your rental portfolio, try buying a piece of property with a partner. Many young people don’t think of real estate as a great partnership opportunity, but it can be. With the right agreements in place and the right vehicles to own real estate, there are easy, effective ways for people to buy real estate with a partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s tips or purchasing real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-ways-young-people-can-build-wealth-through-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-ways-young-people-can-build-wealth-through-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Dramatically Increase Your Home’s Value in 2021?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g76qRzjWLpE?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here's what homebuyers are willing to pay a premium for in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to add tens of thousands of dollars of value to your home this year, there are a couple of key things you can do. While these may be some big-ticket items that you’ll need to purchase, your investment will bring fantastic returns in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the pandemic began, we’ve seen pools and backyards explode in popularity. Everyone wants a place where they can relax, spread out, and entertain guests safely, so many clients have been investing in their outdoor spaces. &lt;strong&gt;Those who have added pools, which could cost $50,000 to $100,000, are often getting back $150,000 or more on their investment when they sell.&lt;/strong&gt; However, not all homes will gain value when a pool is added; in some cases, you might get a better return if you simply move without pouring money into your property. Either way, we always invite people to reach out to us so we can weigh the options together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio sheds, or accessory dwelling units (ADUs), are also becoming extremely popular.&lt;/strong&gt; Some people believe adding one would be a daunting task, but it’s actually quite easy. Some websites even have prefabricated options that you’re able to choose from. San Diego also has pre-approved plans homeowners can purchase to add ADUs to their property. Homeowners can use this as a way to create secondary income through a rental, or have a private place where relatives can stay. It gives people a lot of flexibility, and homebuyers are flocking to listings that include these units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many clients have been investing in their outdoor spaces.%20http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-dramatically-increase-your-homes-value-in-2021.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many clients have been investing in their outdoor spaces.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate or would like to learn about more ways to add value to your home, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-dramatically-increase-your-homes-value-in-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-dramatically-increase-your-homes-value-in-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why San Diego is in the Midst of a Home Inventory Shortage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B7KwDTe4BtY?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s why demand is so high and supply is so low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling to find a home in the San Diego area, you’re not alone. Inventory has been overwhelmingly low, meaning that tons of buyers are competing over a small supply of properties. Many clients have been wondering why there are so few homes available, which is why we’re covering the top three reasons why San Diego and the rest of the country are experiencing an inventory shortage. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s what’s happening:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The COVID-19 pandemic:&lt;/strong&gt; In the past year, many would-be sellers have decided to wait on listing their homes until the pandemic has passed. Whether they’re immunocompromised or simply uncomfortable putting their homes on the market, fewer people are listing properties. This is the case in San Diego, and high demand from buyers means that inventory is at record-low levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inventory has been overwhelmingly low, meaning that tons of buyers are competing over a small supply of properties.%20http://localhost:4000/why-san-diego-is-in-the-midst-of-a-home-inventory-shortage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inventory has been overwhelmingly low, meaning that tons of buyers are competing over a small supply of properties.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Low interest rates:&lt;/strong&gt; Many people who were thinking of downsizing or moving laterally decided it would make more sense to take advantage of low interest rates, refinance their homes, and come out with a cheaper monthly payment. This is especially true for baby boomers, who hold the largest share of real estate; they’re able to wait longer to move because they now have more options and can better afford payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Longer life expectancy:&lt;/strong&gt; Baby boomers are also enjoying longer, healthier, and more functional lives. They’re also able to stay near their kids and grandchildren instead of moving to less expensive areas. In the past, older adults would typically be downsizing in their 60s and 70s, so this has locked down a lot of real estate. On top of this, San Diego isn’t able to have a lot of single-story homes, so this creates even more competition for the ones that are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help jumping into the market, have any questions, or would like more information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you and helping with any and all of your real estate needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-san-diego-is-in-the-midst-of-a-home-inventory-shortage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-san-diego-is-in-the-midst-of-a-home-inventory-shortage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell a Home Simultaneously</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O60z2PqWk4M?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are three tips to help make your home purchase easier in this market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Looking to buy a home in 2020 but need to sell your current home first? You’re in luck; today I have three great tips on how to accomplish these dual transactions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Get pre-approved.&lt;/strong&gt; Most homebuyers use financing in today’s market, but with the dip in interest rates, you’d be surprised what you can qualify for without selling your current home. Many times, folks realize they can afford the new house without having to sell first. We always have people get pre-approved so they know their options and are financially comfortable with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=For some families, a rent-back might be the only option.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-simultaneously.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“For some families, a rent-back might be the only option.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Start prepping your home for departure.&lt;/strong&gt; While you’re looking for homes online, talk with an agent about a plan to prep your home for departure. A lot of times, homeowners think about doing something, find the perfect home, then lose out on it because their current home isn’t properly prepared first. Sit down with your agent and come up with a gameplan to move from point A to point B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Negotiate a rent-back agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; Since the market is so hot, we’re typically able to get rent-back agreements for our clients so they can sell their home, become completely liquid, then buy and close on the next house without worry. For families, this might be the only option, and today’s buyers are OK with longer rent-back periods as long as they can secure the home to purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about how we can help you get started on the buying or selling process or concerning real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-simultaneously.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-simultaneously.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Seller Tips to Make the Most of the Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S52tBW9QOY4?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I'm sharing three tips to help you sell your home quickly and for the most money.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The market has been hot for the last several months, and it will probably remain that way for a while. Today I want to share three tips to help you make the most of the market when it comes time for you to sell your home:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t just declutter—deep clean, too&lt;/strong&gt;. Too many people think that they can simply box up some of their stuff and be good to go. I’m sure you’ve walked into a home that was decluttered but still felt dirty, and that’s what you want to avoid. The psychology of today’s buyers has changed quite a bit; they’re very cognizant of their environment when they walk through a home, even if they’re not touching things. Spending a few extra bucks to deep clean your house (or doing it yourself) will make a huge difference when receiving offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Perfect preparation makes for a perfect home sale&lt;/strong&gt;. Typically when we sit down with clients, they have between a couple of days and a couple of weeks of preparation needed to make sure the home is in a condition that people are excited about. We want to create the same kind of environment that new construction homes tend to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Hire a top-quality agent&lt;/strong&gt;. You need to work with an agent who will not only tell you the truth, but also guide you through the process so that you can close escrow and sell your house for the most money possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or we can be of assistance to you in any way, please reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-seller-tips-to-make-the-most-of-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-seller-tips-to-make-the-most-of-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to List Before Spring</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KvmEetDC_b0?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have three good reasons you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t wait until spring to sell.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Are you considering listing your home in the spring or summer? You may want to rethink that timeline because now is an excellent time to list your house for sale. Listing between January and March may help you beat out the competition for three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Low competition&lt;/strong&gt;. The competition itself will be lower before spring hits. We’re already seeing a massive amount of competition right now due to the reduced supply of properties on the market. Six months ago your neighborhood may have had five or six homes for sale, but today there may only be one. Less competition gives you the freedom to consider your next move without as many speed bumps in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pent-up buyer demand&lt;/strong&gt;. People were looking to buy in the second half of 2020, but there wasn’t enough inventory on the market. San Diego recorded the lowest amount of inventory ever in the fourth quarter. Our market won’t come out of that until at least late February or March when more people start listing. By that time, we’re into the traditional selling season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, people wait until after the Super Bowl to put their houses on the market, then we get even more in May and June from the family-dense neighborhoods because they want to wait until the kids are out of school. Virtual schooling has changed much of that, so people have the flexibility to move now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is an excellent time to list your house for sale.%20http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-list-before-spring.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is an excellent time to list your house for sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your home’s little-known features can be shown&lt;/strong&gt;. How many of you have a beautiful fire pit with fantastic lighting or heaters, or some other great feature? As people are spending more time at home, they’re paying more attention to these details. They want to walk into a home and see that elegant fireplace lit up, as opposed to dormant, the way it is the rest of the year here in San Diego. They want to see these features utilized because they’ll be spending much of their time at home for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you might be interested in listing your house this winter and want help to compose a plan to win in 2021, we’d love to assist you. Call or leave us a message, and let us know how we can serve you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-list-before-spring.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-list-before-spring.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can I Win in This Competitive Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YUCbbkFoVnA?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Here&amp;rsquo;s how we&amp;rsquo;re helping our clients compete in this tough market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Are you looking to buy a home but frustrated by the intense competition in today’s market? &lt;strong&gt;Last year was a whirlwind, and the biggest thing on every buyer’s mind is how tough it was to compete.&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone’s looking for that competitive edge to help them secure the home they want. Here are three tips that will help get you there:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Get specific.&lt;/strong&gt; The key to finding what you want is getting specific on the house and the location that you want. We do a lot of things when it comes time to finding homes in particular locations that help our buyers win. To be on the winning side, you need a winning agent. It’s already tough enough to view homes on your own. Having an agent will make it easier. They can help you find homes that aren’t actually on the market, too. There are many opportunities out there for buyers to secure homes like these and we’ve had a lot of success matching our buyer and seller clients in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An experienced agent with many connections is an invaluable resource.%20http://localhost:4000/how-can-i-win-in-this-competitive-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An experienced agent with many connections is an invaluable resource.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Use our buyer direct program.&lt;/strong&gt; This allows us to target our search area and call, mail, and leave doorknockers for all the area homeowners where you’re looking and retarget them on social media. This allows us to bring you a property with the least amount of competition since it’s not actually on the market. Some sellers don’t want to go through the minutiae of putting their home on the market, and this program is dedicated to helping buyers win those homes today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Work with an experienced agent.&lt;/strong&gt; They should be well-intertwined with the agent community. So much real estate business gets done through agent communication, and who you work with matters more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to be the agents who help you win, so if you’re looking for more tips and tricks or just have any real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-i-win-in-this-competitive-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-i-win-in-this-competitive-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weighing Your Current Refinancing Options</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3RWs0Uidizo?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Should you refinance now or wait for lower rates? Here&amp;rsquo;s my advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With interest rates as low as they are, a lot of our clients have been reaching out to ask if they should refinance. These are the lowest rates that we’ve ever seen, with some of our clients locking in rates below 2%. We know that the Federal Reserve has gone on record saying they won’t increase rates anytime soon, but should you wait? Well, on one hand, we don’t know what additional costs might be introduced by lenders down the road, but we do know that &lt;strong&gt;right now you can lock in a low interest rate&lt;/strong&gt; and get the best possible financing for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me or would like to get connected with a great local lender, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/weighing-your-current-refinancing-options.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/weighing-your-current-refinancing-options.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are So Many People Moving to San Diego?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-8WAPm1b-QQ?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our market has seen an increase in buyer demand for a few reasons.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The San Diego real estate market is hot, but where are all these buyers coming from? &lt;strong&gt;The majority of them are move-up buyers; that’s the main market today&lt;/strong&gt;. People are moving out of townhomes and condos and looking for more space. We’re also seeing many people move here from comparatively dense cities like Seattle, San Francisco, and Los Angeles to find more space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons they’re moving here are that our weather is excellent, we have the lifestyle people want, we have beaches, and we have housing that’s a little more affordable than other similar areas. We’re also seeing people leaving states with colder weather, where they know they’ll be working from home for a while. For those who know they aren’t going back into the office anytime soon, it’s the perfect time to move here to San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more tips for how to win in the San Diego real estate market or have any questions, feel free to reach out to us via phone or email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-are-so-many-people-moving-to-san-diego.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-are-so-many-people-moving-to-san-diego.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Makes the End of 2020 a Good Time to Buy?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-J_r3mjbHjs?autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our market is moving fast, but here&amp;rsquo;s why it may behoove buyers to act now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re a potential homebuyer wondering whether it’s best to make a move before the calendar turns over or wait until spring 2021, here are three critical considerations to make:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interest rates are at historic lows&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ve probably been seeing this in headlines for almost a year now, but rates just dipped below 3% for the very first time. We’ve been helping buyers left and right lock in rates in the upper 2s on great pieces of real estate. If you’re discouraged about rising home prices, consider that rates have a much more significant impact on your mortgage payment schedule. Though it may seem counterintuitive, buyers today can afford more home for their money than in years past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You can move into a new home with more space&lt;/strong&gt;. This year, we’ve all realized just how important it is to have adequate living space. We’ve already helped scores of families move up from a townhome or condo into a home with more rooms and a yard. Is your family expecting a brand-new member soon? Are you having parents or grandparents move in to create more of a multigenerational lifestyle? If an upgrade is on your horizon, consider acting now; there’s never been a better time to leverage your purchasing power and move up into a larger dwelling space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You can move into a home away from the city&lt;/strong&gt;. When companies began allowing their employees to work from home, many people realized that the only thing they liked about living in the denser urban areas of San Diego was the close proximity to their place of work. Now that these employees can work virtually from anywhere, they’re looking at real estate in the extremities of San Diego where they would have never considered living before. Places like Poway, Fallbrook, North Escondido, and other areas just outside of the city are now hot markets, and it’s more than likely that they’ll become even more competitive as we enter 2021; if you’re one of the many city dwellers looking for more elbow room, it may be best to act now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the things to consider as a homebuyer in the fourth quarter of 2020. If you want more tips and tricks on how to win in the San Diego real estate market, please feel free to give us a call or send an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-makes-the-end-of-2020-a-good-time-to-buy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-makes-the-end-of-2020-a-good-time-to-buy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
