<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://seanzanganeh.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://seanzanganeh.com"/>
    <description>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes & Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Sean Zanganeh</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2016-11-29 16:43:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Sean Zanganeh</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://seanzanganeh.com/img/Zanganeh_podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Sean@MySDDreamHome.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://seanzanganeh.com/img/Zanganeh_podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Del Mar, CA Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes & Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Biggest Mistakes Home Sellers Make</title>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/the-3-biggest-mistakes-home-sellers-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Avoid+these+mistakes+when+selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It seems that home sellers keep making the same mistakes over and over in San Diego. We want you to be aware of these common mistakes so you avoid making them when it comes time to sell your home. Here are three big home selling mistakes to avoid:

1. Incorrect pricing. Price is very important in San Diego, and we notice that when consumers see a home priced accurately, they will not only pay more, but they will take action quicker. We want to sell your home for top dollar in the shortest amount of time, so we always recommend pricing at the market value for the best results.

2. Making your home hard to show. Some buyers may just be in town for a weekend or a few days and only have a limited time frame for when they can look at homes. We try to give our sellers as much advance notice as possible, but it’s also important that sellers be as flexible as they can while their home is on the market. A buyer might only have one opportunity to buy your home, so don’t send them away.

3. Lack of marketing exposure. Sometimes sellers want to just test the market or be a “secret seller.” However, if you’re actively trying to sell your home, you need exposure. You have to get your home out there online, get it seen, and continue to promote it to buyers in the area.

“Being a ‘secret seller’ won’t do you any good.”

If you have any questions for us or need some more advice for getting your home sold, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Avoid+these+mistakes+when+selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://seanzanganeh.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Avoid+these+mistakes+when+selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Del Mar, CA Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are many mistakes that can be made during a home sale. Here are three of them you should avoid above all else.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Fall Market Impacts Your San Diego Home</title>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/how-the-fall-market-impacts-your-san-diego-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Examining+Fall+Real+Estate+Market+Trends.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Let’s take a look at the fall market and what we can expect for the rest of the year.

I’m constantly asked if I think we’re in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market, but I actually think it’s a neutral market. What does that mean to you? If you’re a buyer, you benefit from interest rates still being super low. We’re seeing buyers get great deals on properties, and the opportunities for these deals will continue as we head into the winter months.

“Smart real estate decisions are keeping our market moving forward.”

What about sellers? Inventory is still tight in our market, meaning there are not a lot of homes for sale. Sellers are getting multiple offers on properties, and we see a lot of energy around listings. This means that there are definitely buyers out there for homes. With interest rates as low as they are, many buyers are taking action.

It’s going to be a wacky election year and a lot of things are going to change, but our local market shouldn’t be affected much. We still have a lot of people who are looking to buy or sell, and smart real estate decisions are moving our market forward.

If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to work with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Examining+Fall+Real+Estate+Market+Trends.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://seanzanganeh.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Examining+Fall+Real+Estate+Market+Trends.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Del Mar, CA Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We're seeing some interesting trends in the fall real estate market. What does this mean for you? What does it mean for our market moving forward?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Our New Video Blog</title>
        <link>http://seanzanganeh.com/welcome-to-our-new-video-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Youtube+Intro.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve got some exciting news to report to you all today.

We’ll be sharing our real estate expertise with you through our new video blog. We’re extremely excited about this and we want to be sure to include all of you. Here’s how it will work:

Each month, we’ll send out two emails addressing trends in our local real estate market. We’ll also be sharing real estate tips for San Diego, what’s going on in the market, and even what’s going on in your neighborhood.
 “We’d love to answer your specific questions about the real estate market.”
Rather than simply guess what’s on your mind, though, we’d like to reach out and ask you all what kinds of questions you have. Are there any concepts you’re unclear about? Are you curious about the market in your particular area or neighborhood? Our goal is to build the best possible library about San Diego real estate and answer your specific questions in our videos so that other people with similar questions can benefit from them, too.

Until next time, if you’ve got any questions about real estate that you’d like us to address, please don’t hesitate to call us or send us an email. We look forward to producing great content that will be helpful for your real estate journey!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Youtube+Intro.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://seanzanganeh.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Youtube+Intro.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Del Mar, CA Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Exciting news: I’ll be sharing my real estate expertise with you through my new video blog!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Sean Zanganeh</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Sean Zanganeh</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes & Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>