<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes & Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Sean Zanganeh</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2021-10-12 11:43:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Sean Zanganeh</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/Zanganeh_podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Sean@MySDDreamHome.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/Zanganeh_podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Del Mar, CA Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes & Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways Young People Can Build Wealth Through Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-ways-young-people-can-build-wealth-through-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-04-28 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/3+Ways+Young+People+Can+Build+Wealth+Through+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are three ways to build your real estate portfolio in San Diego.

Many first-time homebuyers are looking to purchase homes, but they’re finding that prices are just too high for them. I’d both agree and disagree with their assessments; it all depends on what you’re looking at. Today I’ll share three great ways to help you build your portfolio and wealth here in San Diego:

1. Condos. In today’s market, condos are probably the most underrated asset class. Over the last 12 to 18 months, so many people have shifted their focus to single-family homes that the condo market has softened and people are getting deals. Post pandemic, we’ll likely see the condo market come back strong as people use them for second homes and other purposes. I’ve seen a ton of clients gain lots of equity from condos, and it’s substantially easier to get into that market than the detached housing market these days.

“Many young people don’t think of real estate as a great partnership opportunity, but it can be.”

2. “House hack” by renting out bought property. House hacking is where you purchase a large or multi-unit property and rent it out to tenants. The rent you receive can offset the cost of the property. Suppose you had a two-unit property in a desirable location where you couldn’t normally qualify for two units at $750,000. By purchasing a two-unit property there, you can use the rent generated to offset the property’s expenses, so it might feel like you’re only buying a $500,000 property. This is useful for those who want to live with another person.

3. Buy real estate with someone. If you’re looking to start your rental portfolio, try buying a piece of property with a partner. Many young people don’t think of real estate as a great partnership opportunity, but it can be. With the right agreements in place and the right vehicles to own real estate, there are easy, effective ways for people to buy real estate with a partner.

If you have any questions about today’s tips or purchasing real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/3+Ways+Young+People+Can+Build+Wealth+Through+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/3+Ways+Young+People+Can+Build+Wealth+Through+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are three ways to build your real estate portfolio in San Diego.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are three ways to build your real estate portfolio in San Diego.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Dramatically Increase Your Home’s Value in 2021?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-dramatically-increase-your-homes-value-in-2021.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-04-08 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+Can+You+Dramatically+Increase+Your+Home%E2%80%99s+Value+in+2021_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here's what homebuyers are willing to pay a premium for in 2021.

If you’re looking to add tens of thousands of dollars of value to your home this year, there are a couple of key things you can do. While these may be some big-ticket items that you’ll need to purchase, your investment will bring fantastic returns in the future.

Since the pandemic began, we’ve seen pools and backyards explode in popularity. Everyone wants a place where they can relax, spread out, and entertain guests safely, so many clients have been investing in their outdoor spaces. Those who have added pools, which could cost $50,000 to $100,000, are often getting back $150,000 or more on their investment when they sell. However, not all homes will gain value when a pool is added; in some cases, you might get a better return if you simply move without pouring money into your property. Either way, we always invite people to reach out to us so we can weigh the options together.

Studio sheds, or accessory dwelling units (ADUs), are also becoming extremely popular. Some people believe adding one would be a daunting task, but it’s actually quite easy. Some websites even have prefabricated options that you’re able to choose from. San Diego also has pre-approved plans homeowners can purchase to add ADUs to their property. Homeowners can use this as a way to create secondary income through a rental, or have a private place where relatives can stay. It gives people a lot of flexibility, and homebuyers are flocking to listings that include these units.

“Many clients have been investing in their outdoor spaces.”

If you have any questions about real estate or would like to learn about more ways to add value to your home, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+Can+You+Dramatically+Increase+Your+Home%E2%80%99s+Value+in+2021_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+Can+You+Dramatically+Increase+Your+Home%E2%80%99s+Value+in+2021_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here's what homebuyers are willing to pay a premium for in 2021.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here's what homebuyers are willing to pay a premium for in 2021.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why San Diego is in the Midst of a Home Inventory Shortage</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-san-diego-is-in-the-midst-of-a-home-inventory-shortage.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-03-29 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/Why+San+Diego+is+in+the+Midst+of+a+Home+Inventory+Shortage.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s why demand is so high and supply is so low.

If you’re struggling to find a home in the San Diego area, you’re not alone. Inventory has been overwhelmingly low, meaning that tons of buyers are competing over a small supply of properties. Many clients have been wondering why there are so few homes available, which is why we’re covering the top three reasons why San Diego and the rest of the country are experiencing an inventory shortage. Here’s what’s happening:

1. The COVID-19 pandemic: In the past year, many would-be sellers have decided to wait on listing their homes until the pandemic has passed. Whether they’re immunocompromised or simply uncomfortable putting their homes on the market, fewer people are listing properties. This is the case in San Diego, and high demand from buyers means that inventory is at record-low levels.

“Inventory has been overwhelmingly low, meaning that tons of buyers are competing over a small supply of properties.”

2. Low interest rates: Many people who were thinking of downsizing or moving laterally decided it would make more sense to take advantage of low interest rates, refinance their homes, and come out with a cheaper monthly payment. This is especially true for baby boomers, who hold the largest share of real estate; they’re able to wait longer to move because they now have more options and can better afford payments.

3. Longer life expectancy: Baby boomers are also enjoying longer, healthier, and more functional lives. They’re also able to stay near their kids and grandchildren instead of moving to less expensive areas. In the past, older adults would typically be downsizing in their 60s and 70s, so this has locked down a lot of real estate. On top of this, San Diego isn’t able to have a lot of single-story homes, so this creates even more competition for the ones that are available.

If you need help jumping into the market, have any questions, or would like more information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you and helping with any and all of your real estate needs.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/Why+San+Diego+is+in+the+Midst+of+a+Home+Inventory+Shortage.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/Why+San+Diego+is+in+the+Midst+of+a+Home+Inventory+Shortage.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s why demand is so high and supply is so low.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s why demand is so high and supply is so low.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell a Home Simultaneously</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-simultaneously.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-03-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+Simultaneously.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are three tips to help make your home purchase easier in this market.

Looking to buy a home in 2020 but need to sell your current home first? You’re in luck; today I have three great tips on how to accomplish these dual transactions:

1. Get pre-approved. Most homebuyers use financing in today’s market, but with the dip in interest rates, you’d be surprised what you can qualify for without selling your current home. Many times, folks realize they can afford the new house without having to sell first. We always have people get pre-approved so they know their options and are financially comfortable with them.

“For some families, a rent-back might be the only option.”

2. Start prepping your home for departure. While you’re looking for homes online, talk with an agent about a plan to prep your home for departure. A lot of times, homeowners think about doing something, find the perfect home, then lose out on it because their current home isn’t properly prepared first. Sit down with your agent and come up with a gameplan to move from point A to point B.

3. Negotiate a rent-back agreement. Since the market is so hot, we’re typically able to get rent-back agreements for our clients so they can sell their home, become completely liquid, then buy and close on the next house without worry. For families, this might be the only option, and today’s buyers are OK with longer rent-back periods as long as they can secure the home to purchase.

If you have questions about how we can help you get started on the buying or selling process or concerning real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+Simultaneously.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+Simultaneously.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are three tips to help make your home purchase easier in this market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are three tips to help make your home purchase easier in this market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Seller Tips to Make the Most of the Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-seller-tips-to-make-the-most-of-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-02-28 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I'm sharing three tips to help you sell your home quickly and for the most money.

The market has been hot for the last several months, and it will probably remain that way for a while. Today I want to share three tips to help you make the most of the market when it comes time for you to sell your home:

1. Don’t just declutter—deep clean, too. Too many people think that they can simply box up some of their stuff and be good to go. I’m sure you’ve walked into a home that was decluttered but still felt dirty, and that’s what you want to avoid. The psychology of today’s buyers has changed quite a bit; they’re very cognizant of their environment when they walk through a home, even if they’re not touching things. Spending a few extra bucks to deep clean your house (or doing it yourself) will make a huge difference when receiving offers.

2. Perfect preparation makes for a perfect home sale. Typically when we sit down with clients, they have between a couple of days and a couple of weeks of preparation needed to make sure the home is in a condition that people are excited about. We want to create the same kind of environment that new construction homes tend to have.

3. Hire a top-quality agent. You need to work with an agent who will not only tell you the truth, but also guide you through the process so that you can close escrow and sell your house for the most money possible.

If you have questions or we can be of assistance to you in any way, please reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m sharing three tips to help you sell your home quickly and for the most money.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m sharing three tips to help you sell your home quickly and for the most money.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to List Before Spring</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-list-before-spring.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-01-18 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/3+Reasons+to+List+Before+Spring.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have three good reasons you shouldn&rsquo;t wait until spring to sell.

Are you considering listing your home in the spring or summer? You may want to rethink that timeline because now is an excellent time to list your house for sale. Listing between January and March may help you beat out the competition for three reasons:

1. Low competition. The competition itself will be lower before spring hits. We’re already seeing a massive amount of competition right now due to the reduced supply of properties on the market. Six months ago your neighborhood may have had five or six homes for sale, but today there may only be one. Less competition gives you the freedom to consider your next move without as many speed bumps in the way.

2. Pent-up buyer demand. People were looking to buy in the second half of 2020, but there wasn’t enough inventory on the market. San Diego recorded the lowest amount of inventory ever in the fourth quarter. Our market won’t come out of that until at least late February or March when more people start listing. By that time, we’re into the traditional selling season.

Usually, people wait until after the Super Bowl to put their houses on the market, then we get even more in May and June from the family-dense neighborhoods because they want to wait until the kids are out of school. Virtual schooling has changed much of that, so people have the flexibility to move now.

“Now is an excellent time to list your house for sale.”

3. Your home’s little-known features can be shown. How many of you have a beautiful fire pit with fantastic lighting or heaters, or some other great feature? As people are spending more time at home, they’re paying more attention to these details. They want to walk into a home and see that elegant fireplace lit up, as opposed to dormant, the way it is the rest of the year here in San Diego. They want to see these features utilized because they’ll be spending much of their time at home for the foreseeable future.

If you might be interested in listing your house this winter and want help to compose a plan to win in 2021, we’d love to assist you. Call or leave us a message, and let us know how we can serve you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/3+Reasons+to+List+Before+Spring.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/3+Reasons+to+List+Before+Spring.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have three good reasons you shouldn’t wait until spring to sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have three good reasons you shouldn’t wait until spring to sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can I Win in This Competitive Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-i-win-in-this-competitive-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2021-01-04 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+Can+I+Win+in+This+Competitive+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

&nbsp;Here&rsquo;s how we&rsquo;re helping our clients compete in this tough market.

Are you looking to buy a home but frustrated by the intense competition in today’s market? Last year was a whirlwind, and the biggest thing on every buyer’s mind is how tough it was to compete. Everyone’s looking for that competitive edge to help them secure the home they want. Here are three tips that will help get you there:

1. Get specific. The key to finding what you want is getting specific on the house and the location that you want. We do a lot of things when it comes time to finding homes in particular locations that help our buyers win. To be on the winning side, you need a winning agent. It’s already tough enough to view homes on your own. Having an agent will make it easier. They can help you find homes that aren’t actually on the market, too. There are many opportunities out there for buyers to secure homes like these and we’ve had a lot of success matching our buyer and seller clients in the past.

“An experienced agent with many connections is an invaluable resource.”

2. Use our buyer direct program. This allows us to target our search area and call, mail, and leave doorknockers for all the area homeowners where you’re looking and retarget them on social media. This allows us to bring you a property with the least amount of competition since it’s not actually on the market. Some sellers don’t want to go through the minutiae of putting their home on the market, and this program is dedicated to helping buyers win those homes today.

3. Work with an experienced agent. They should be well-intertwined with the agent community. So much real estate business gets done through agent communication, and who you work with matters more than ever.

We want to be the agents who help you win, so if you’re looking for more tips and tricks or just have any real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+Can+I+Win+in+This+Competitive+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2021/How+Can+I+Win+in+This+Competitive+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how we’re helping our clients compete in this tough market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how we’re helping our clients compete in this tough market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Weighing Your Current Refinancing Options</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/weighing-your-current-refinancing-options.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-12-17 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Weighing+Your+Current+Refinancing+Options.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Should you refinance now or wait for lower rates? Here&rsquo;s my advice.

With interest rates as low as they are, a lot of our clients have been reaching out to ask if they should refinance. These are the lowest rates that we’ve ever seen, with some of our clients locking in rates below 2%. We know that the Federal Reserve has gone on record saying they won’t increase rates anytime soon, but should you wait? Well, on one hand, we don’t know what additional costs might be introduced by lenders down the road, but we do know that right now you can lock in a low interest rate and get the best possible financing for your home.

If you have any other questions for me or would like to get connected with a great local lender, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Weighing+Your+Current+Refinancing+Options.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Weighing+Your+Current+Refinancing+Options.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Should you refinance now or wait for lower rates? Here’s my advice.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Should you refinance now or wait for lower rates? Here’s my advice.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Are So Many People Moving to San Diego?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-are-so-many-people-moving-to-san-diego.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-12-02 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Why+Are+So+Many+People+Moving+to+San+Diego_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market has seen an increase in buyer demand for a few reasons.

The San Diego real estate market is hot, but where are all these buyers coming from? The majority of them are move-up buyers; that’s the main market today. People are moving out of townhomes and condos and looking for more space. We’re also seeing many people move here from comparatively dense cities like Seattle, San Francisco, and Los Angeles to find more space.

Some of the reasons they’re moving here are that our weather is excellent, we have the lifestyle people want, we have beaches, and we have housing that’s a little more affordable than other similar areas. We’re also seeing people leaving states with colder weather, where they know they’ll be working from home for a while. For those who know they aren’t going back into the office anytime soon, it’s the perfect time to move here to San Diego.

If you want more tips for how to win in the San Diego real estate market or have any questions, feel free to reach out to us via phone or email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Why+Are+So+Many+People+Moving+to+San+Diego_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Why+Are+So+Many+People+Moving+to+San+Diego_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market has seen an increase in buyer demand for a few reasons.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market has seen an increase in buyer demand for a few reasons.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Makes the End of 2020 a Good Time to Buy?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-makes-the-end-of-2020-a-good-time-to-buy.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-17 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/What+Makes+the+End+of+2020+a+Good+Time+to+Buy_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market is moving fast, but here&rsquo;s why it may behoove buyers to act now.

If you’re a potential homebuyer wondering whether it’s best to make a move before the calendar turns over or wait until spring 2021, here are three critical considerations to make:

1. Interest rates are at historic lows. You’ve probably been seeing this in headlines for almost a year now, but rates just dipped below 3% for the very first time. We’ve been helping buyers left and right lock in rates in the upper 2s on great pieces of real estate. If you’re discouraged about rising home prices, consider that rates have a much more significant impact on your mortgage payment schedule. Though it may seem counterintuitive, buyers today can afford more home for their money than in years past.

2. You can move into a new home with more space. This year, we’ve all realized just how important it is to have adequate living space. We’ve already helped scores of families move up from a townhome or condo into a home with more rooms and a yard. Is your family expecting a brand-new member soon? Are you having parents or grandparents move in to create more of a multigenerational lifestyle? If an upgrade is on your horizon, consider acting now; there’s never been a better time to leverage your purchasing power and move up into a larger dwelling space.

3. You can move into a home away from the city. When companies began allowing their employees to work from home, many people realized that the only thing they liked about living in the denser urban areas of San Diego was the close proximity to their place of work. Now that these employees can work virtually from anywhere, they’re looking at real estate in the extremities of San Diego where they would have never considered living before. Places like Poway, Fallbrook, North Escondido, and other areas just outside of the city are now hot markets, and it’s more than likely that they’ll become even more competitive as we enter 2021; if you’re one of the many city dwellers looking for more elbow room, it may be best to act now.

These are just a few of the things to consider as a homebuyer in the fourth quarter of 2020. If you want more tips and tricks on how to win in the San Diego real estate market, please feel free to give us a call or send an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/What+Makes+the+End+of+2020+a+Good+Time+to+Buy_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/What+Makes+the+End+of+2020+a+Good+Time+to+Buy_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is moving fast, but here’s why it may behoove buyers to act now.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is moving fast, but here’s why it may behoove buyers to act now.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q4 Market Update: What is Going to Happen to Your Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q4-market-update-what-is-going-to-happen-to-your-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-03 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Q4+Market+Update+What+is+Going+to+Happen+to+Your+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Low inventory, low rates, and a shift in demand are fueling our Q4 market.

Our fourth quarter San Diego market is as hot as ever, and one of the main driving factors is our low inventory, which continues to push home appreciation upward. Right now, there are fewer than 4,000 homes available on the market, meaning we have only 1.6 to 1.8 months’ worth of inventory. In other words, if no other homes were to come onto the market, all the existing homes for sale would be snatched up in just under 60 days. This scarcity has caused an 11% year-over-year increase in home prices. Even buyers we helped earlier in the year are saying to themselves, “Wow, there’s a lot more equity in my home than I thought there would be by now!”

Though ours is a seller’s market, good loans, cash purchases, and strong buyers characterize the consistent demand we’ve been seeing this year. Behind all that demand is the ever-alluring incentive of cheap money; interest rates have hit record lows on several different occasions in 2020. New construction homes, highly rehabbed or flipped homes, and heavily remodeled properties are all selling for a premium right now.

We’re seeing a shift in demand so radical and widespread that it’s transforming the normally quiet surrounding markets into hotspots. Today’s buyers are seeking big backyards, home offices, casitas, and family compounds for multigenerational living. For the last six or seven months, it seems that the traffic in San Diego is down, and that’s because countless companies have switched to remote operations, eliminating the morning commute for many workers.

“These are likely the lowest interest rates we’ll see in our lifetime.”

No longer needing to live close to the office, many buyers are eagerly exploring areas they’d previously ruled out as impractical or downright impossible—places like Poway, Jamul, La Mesa, Fallbrook, etc. Whereas the trend up until recently has been a westward migration toward coastal Cali living, people today are turning around and moving back inland.

I’ve already mentioned them above, but those low interest rates deserve special attention; they’re truly a driving force in our market. Right now, we’re seeing borrowers lock in rates lower than 3%. (Some super-qualified buyers have even seen rates below 2%). While not everyone will be able to get a record-breaking rate, the majority of people are still able to get a fantastic one. These are likely the lowest interest rates we’ll see in our lifetime.

So, if you’re looking to capitalize on these unique conditions or have any real estate-related questions, give us a call or send an email. We know that 2021 will bring even more changes to our market, so we at the Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Team want to be there to help you plan.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Q4+Market+Update+What+is+Going+to+Happen+to+Your+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Q4+Market+Update+What+is+Going+to+Happen+to+Your+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Low inventory, low rates, and a shift in demand are fueling our Q4 market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Low inventory, low rates, and a shift in demand are fueling our Q4 market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How We Can Help You in 2020</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-we-can-help-you-in-2020.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-01 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+We+Can+Help+You+in+2020.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We want to help you reach your real estate goals, even amid COVID-19.

The world has changed so much in 2020. We’ve been checking on our friends, family, and clients to make sure you’re all doing well. During these conversations, we’ve been receiving many questions from you about the market, home prices, and more.

Today I wanted to share how we can help you during this peculiar time. We want to provide accurate information to help you make the best decisions for you and your family.

You’re home has probably gone up in price more than you think, so we should chat if you’re even having a thought about selling. If you’d like to set up a call to discuss the value of your home, visit our Calendly link below and select a time that works best for you. We look forward to speaking with you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+We+Can+Help+You+in+2020.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+We+Can+Help+You+in+2020.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We want to help you reach your real estate goals, even amid COVID-19.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We want to help you reach your real estate goals, even amid COVID-19.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Still Sell for Top Dollar?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-you-still-sell-for-top-dollar.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-24 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Can+You+Still+Sell+for+Top+Dollar_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You can still sell for top dollar amid COVID-19. Here&rsquo;s how we do it.

Can you still get top dollar for your home in today’s real estate market? Amid all the negative news lately, I’m sharing one of my recent clients’ success stories.

One of the key things we’re seeing in this new state of the world is that marketing a house is more crucial than ever. Video, high-resolution photography, and 3D tours have become the baseline for getting a property sold. Despite the coronavirus, there are many people in the market looking for a home.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Can+You+Still+Sell+for+Top+Dollar_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Can+You+Still+Sell+for+Top+Dollar_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can still sell for top dollar amid COVID-19. Here’s how we do it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can still sell for top dollar amid COVID-19. Here’s how we do it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Worried About Buyers Seeing Your Home in Today’s Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/worried-about-buyers-seeing-your-home-in-todays-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-17 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Worried+About+Buyers+Seeing+Your+Home+in+Todays+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have some important news to share with future home sellers.

One of the main concerns we’re hearing from sellers right now is the uncertainty of whether or not there are buyers out looking for homes. I’m here to tell you that buyers are definitely out looking in our market right now.

Although things are operating a little differently than they were before the pandemic, business is still being done nonetheless. After a huge dropoff in showings back in March and April, we’re back to seeing a normal level of activity in our market.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Worried+About+Buyers+Seeing+Your+Home+in+Todays+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Worried+About+Buyers+Seeing+Your+Home+in+Todays+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have some important news to share with future home sellers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have some important news to share with future home sellers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Is Our Market Doing?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-is-our-market-doing.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-11 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+Is+Our+Market+Doing_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you&rsquo;re considering selling, here&rsquo;s what you need to know.

Are you considering selling your home and want to know how the real estate market is doing? Certain indicators demonstrate how the market is faring better than others, and today I’m sharing the ones you need to make the best decisions when selling.

First, we tracked the new properties coming onto the market through April and May, and we actually saw 18% more homes listed, despite the pandemic. When the June statistics come out, we’ll see that number skyrocket.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+Is+Our+Market+Doing_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+Is+Our+Market+Doing_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering selling, here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering selling, here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where’s the Mortgage Market Headed?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wheres-the-mortgage-market-headed.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-18 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Wheres+the+Mortgage+Market+Headed_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Todd Pianin joined me for a great discussion on the state of the mortgage market.

Todd Pianin of Guaranteed Rate has joined me once again to talk about the state of our mortgage market. A lot of people have been asking us about the increased showing traffic and whether or not it has resulted in an increase in mortgage applications. According to Todd, Guaranteed Rate’s volume is going up each month and demand has picked up, especially in the last few weeks. He also discussed jumbo loans, interest rates, and more.

To hear our full conversation, watch the video above.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Wheres+the+Mortgage+Market+Headed_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/Wheres+the+Mortgage+Market+Headed_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Todd Pianin joined me for a great discussion on the state of the mortgage market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Todd Pianin joined me for a great discussion on the state of the mortgage market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How People Are Buying Homes in San Diego Right Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-people-are-buying-homes-in-san-diego-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-03 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+People+Are+Buying+Homes+in+San+Diego+Right+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Buying a home during a pandemic is different than it normally is, but there are still opportunities out there to buy safely and successfully.

Although the COVID-19 pandemic has negatively affected many different areas of our economy, there are still people out there buying and selling homes. Today we’re going to focus on what active buyers are experiencing right now. Many buyers began the process before this crisis happened and need to buy in order to expand their family. The good news is that there are still great opportunities out there for them.

One of the main advantages for homebuyers now is less competition. Our inventory levels are near rock-bottom lows, and instead of competing against 10 other buyers, most are competing against just one or two.

Another opportunity has to do with interest rates. Due to shifts in the stock market, interest rates have become extremely attractive for those who qualify. If you are in the process of looking for a home to buy, make sure you get a pre-approval. If you have one from earlier in the year, make sure you’re getting an updated one. Most agents aren’t looking at pre-approvals that are more than a few weeks old.

“We can help you start your search through virtual, 3D showings.”

Finally, we’re seeing a big shift in terms of how people are viewing properties. We saw showings drop dramatically at the end of March, but they’re up by over 25% in just the last few weeks. Buyers in today’s market are much more interested in virtual tours, Matterport tours, HD photos, and videos than they have been in the past. For-sale homes that provide them are where buyers are starting their search. From there, we can help you figure out what the right fit is to save you time, keep you safe and healthy, and make sure you can find the house of your dreams.

If you have any questions about buying a home, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+People+Are+Buying+Homes+in+San+Diego+Right+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/How+People+Are+Buying+Homes+in+San+Diego+Right+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying a home during a pandemic is different than it normally is, but there are still opportunities out there to buy safely and successfully.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying a home during a pandemic is different than it normally is, but there are still opportunities out there to buy safely and successfully.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Selling Amid the Pandemic: Be Proactive</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-selling-amid-the-pandemic-be-proactive.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/The+Key+to+Selling+Amid+the+Pandemic-+Be+Proactive.mp4</guid>
        <description>

COVID-19 has flipped our world upside down, but the real estate industry is resilient. Here&rsquo;s how we&rsquo;re helping sellers maximize opportunities.

Are homes still selling during the COVID-19 pandemic? If you need to sell, how do you even go about doing so right now? Truthfully, the market is still moving along considerably well. We’re monitoring the MLS and seeing homes in our San Diego market go into escrow every single day—remarkably close to what we’d see under normal conditions. Here’s even more good news: If your home is in a low inventory area or a highly sought-after price point, we’re seeing those prices increase.

The sellers getting top dollar for their homes right now are the ones working with experienced agents who leverage 3D Matterport tours and narrated video walk-throughs to keep prospective buyers well-informed and all parties safe.

Things like high-definition photography, professional videography, and virtual tours have always been powerful tools in the arsenal of elite modern brokerages; now more than ever, these tools are essential to the success of a real estate transaction. We have plenty of experience using various media to get homes maximum exposure on the market, so we’re well-equipped to handle this shift to virtual real estate processes.

“Buyer tastes and overall demand are changing.”

What’s next? Make sure you’re reaching out to a real estate agent and having the conversation now. Buyer tastes and overall demand are changing right now, so the earlier you can prepare your home and set up a game plan for going to market, the better.

If you think you need help with getting your home sold in this unusual environment, please feel free to reach out to us today. We’d love to have a confidential conversation with you and explore your specific situation.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/The+Key+to+Selling+Amid+the+Pandemic-+Be+Proactive.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/2020/The+Key+to+Selling+Amid+the+Pandemic-+Be+Proactive.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>COVID-19 has flipped our world upside down, but the real estate industry is resilient. Here’s how we’re helping sellers maximize opportunities.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>COVID-19 has flipped our world upside down, but the real estate industry is resilient. Here’s how we’re helping sellers maximize opportunities.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Our New Video Blog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-our-new-video-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Youtube+Intro.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve got some exciting news to report to you all today.We’ll be sharing our real estate expertise with you through our new video blog. We’re extremely excited about this and we want to be sure to include all of you. Here’s how it will work:Each month, we’ll send out two emails addressing trends in our local real estate market. We’ll also be sharing real estate tips for San Diego, what’s going on in the market, and even what’s going on in your neighborhood.

“We’d love to answer your specific questions about the real estate market.”

Rather than simply guess what’s on your mind, though, we’d like to reach out and ask you all what kinds of questions you have. Are there any concepts you’re unclear about? Are you curious about the market in your particular area or neighborhood? Our goal is to build the best possible library about San Diego real estate and answer your specific questions in our videos so that other people with similar questions can benefit from them, too.Until next time, if you’ve got any questions about real estate that you’d like us to address, please don’t hesitate to call us or send us an email. We look forward to producing great content that will be helpful for your real estate journey!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Youtube+Intro.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Youtube+Intro.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Exciting news: I’ll be sharing my real estate expertise with you through my new video blog!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Exciting news: I’ll be sharing my real estate expertise with you through my new video blog!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Still Need Valentine’s Day Plans?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/still-need-valentines-day-plans.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Our+Valentine%E2%80%99s+Day+date+recommendations.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As you know, Valentine’s Day is coming up, so we wanted to help those of you who are still struggling to figure out what to do with a few recommendations.

As far as restaurants go, Veladora over at Rancho Valencia, The Market in Del Mar, and Eddie V’s in La Jolla are a couple of our favorites.

“To do something out of the box, consider going to a comedy club!”

If you’re looking to do something a little more outside of the box, consider going to a comedy club or taking a gondola ride down the shores in Coronado. You could also head to The Lot in La Jolla or Point Loma or Synapolis in Del Mar in La Costa to watch your favorite move with cocktails, a full bar, a restaurant, desserts, and more.

If you are looking to buy or sell a home, or if you have any other real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to give us a call. We would be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Our+Valentine%E2%80%99s+Day+date+recommendations.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Our+Valentine%E2%80%99s+Day+date+recommendations.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Valentine’s Day is coming up, so we wanted to give you some recommendations on where and how to make your day special.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Valentine’s Day is coming up, so we wanted to give you some recommendations on where and how to make your day special.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Insure Your Condominiums</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-insure-your-condominiums.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Insure+Your+Condominiums.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you confused about what type of condominium insurance you should purchase?

 

Are you interested in buying a condo but have no idea how to insure it? Condos are insured differently than homes and there are multiple ways we see them show up. Today Seth Arruda of Alta Vista Insurance Agency and I will look at the top three ways we see condos insured as well as the types of insurance that clients get.

There are a number of ways that a homeowners association (HOA) will insure a condo. The most common way is to provide coverage of the exterior of the buildings and the common areas. That leaves the owner of the specific condo to insure the inside of the unit. This is called a unit owner’s policy.

Seth tells us that he has also seen situations where the HOA will only provide coverage for their common areas. This means that you will own your roof, your side, your exterior, and your interior, but you are within a smaller subdivision where there are smaller homes on zero lot lines.

The final way that an HOA can insure a condominium is by providing coverage for the common area and the structures, leaving everything behind the walls in each unit as the responsibility of the unit owner. This means that items such as plumbing lines, service lines, and electrical lines all need to be insured under your unit owner’s policy.

“Try to obtain a copy of your CC&amp;Rs and review the contract with your insurance agent.”

Each type of policy is very specific and it is very important to find out what is covered in each situation. If you own or are looking to purchase a condominium, you should try to obtain a copy of your Covenants, Conditions, &amp; Restrictions (CC&amp;Rs) and review the contract with your insurance agent to ensure your unit is properly protected and that you have the right coverage.

Seth is our contact when it comes to finding insurance in San Diego and has helped us for a long time. If you are looking for a great broker to help you navigate your situation, you can call Seth at (760) 724-2124.

As always if you are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Insure+Your+Condominiums.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Insure+Your+Condominiums.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you confused about what type of condominium insurance you should purchase?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you confused about what type of condominium insurance you should purchase?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Fall Market Impacts Your San Diego Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-the-fall-market-impacts-your-san-diego-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Examining+Fall+Real+Estate+Market+Trends.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Let’s take a look at the fall market and what we can expect for the rest of the year.

I’m constantly asked if I think we’re in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market, but I actually think it’s a neutral market. What does that mean to you? If you’re a buyer, you benefit from interest rates still being super low. We’re seeing buyers get great deals on properties, and the opportunities for these deals will continue as we head into the winter months.

“Smart real estate decisions are keeping our market moving forward.”

What about sellers? Inventory is still tight in our market, meaning there are not a lot of homes for sale. Sellers are getting multiple offers on properties, and we see a lot of energy around listings. This means that there are definitely buyers out there for homes. With interest rates as low as they are, many buyers are taking action.

It’s going to be a wacky election year and a lot of things are going to change, but our local market shouldn’t be affected much. We still have a lot of people who are looking to buy or sell, and smart real estate decisions are moving our market forward.

If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to work with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Examining+Fall+Real+Estate+Market+Trends.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh+Examining+Fall+Real+Estate+Market+Trends.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We're seeing some interesting trends in the fall real estate market. What does this mean for you? What does it mean for our market moving forward?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We're seeing some interesting trends in the fall real estate market. What does this mean for you? What does it mean for our market moving forward?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering All Your Questions About Insurance</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/answering-all-your-questions-about-insurance.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Answering+All+Your+Questions+About+Insurance.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Seth Arruda of Alta Vista Insurance joins me to talk about insurance options to consider when purchasing a home.

 

I am joined by Seth Arruda to talk to you about looking for insurance in the middle of a real estate transaction. I have some tips and tricks which should help you win in the San Diego market.

So, what things must a consumer know to make an educated choice about insurance coverage? Let’s take a look at the five questions consumers should ask themselves.

1. What is covered?2. How much coverage do you need?3. How do you insure your personal property and belongings?4. How do you insure the items which mean the most?5. What about liability?

To start with, what is covered? In California, standard hazard or fire insurance, as everyone likes to call it, insures you for sudden, accidental occurrences and catastrophic perils such as fire, wind, hail, and lightning.

How much coverage does a client need on a house? This is where we get into talking about replacement cost value of a home. Insurance companies insure the structures based on their reconstruction costs, so they are not concerned with the market value of a home.

“In California, standard hazard insurance insures you for sudden, accidental occurrences and catastrophic perils such as fire, wind, hail, and lightning.”

What about insuring personal belongings? You need to make sure that you carry replacement cost value for all the contents in your home. With this insurance, if any of your personal items are destroyed due to a covered peril, you will get the full replacement for those items such as furniture, electronics, clothing, etc.

How do I cover my expensive jewelry, diamonds, gold, collectibles, and antiques? The insurance companies call those items “scheduled personal property,” and you want to make sure that they are itemized on your insurance policy. You will usually need an appraisal or receipt showing the value of the items.

Finally, what do we cover with liability? Liability is attached to your home insurance and will give you liability protection for your residence premises and personal injury matters. You want to have proper liability for things such as libel or slander.

As you can see, there is a lot that goes into insurance, which is why you should have a good insurance broker that can shop several different options. You can contact Seth at (760) 724-2124 if you would like to speak to him about a new policy or modifying your existing policy.

If you are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.

Seth ArrudaAlta Vista Insurance(760) 724-2124altavistainsurance.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Answering+All+Your+Questions+About+Insurance.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Answering+All+Your+Questions+About+Insurance.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Seth Arruda of Alta Vista Insurance joins me to talk about insurance options to consider when purchasing a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Seth Arruda of Alta Vista Insurance joins me to talk about insurance options to consider when purchasing a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Hot Lending Topics for 2018</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-hot-lending-topics-for-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-29 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/3+Hot+Lending+Topics+for+2018.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What&rsquo;s going on in the lending world right now in San Diego? There are three main topics I&rsquo;d like to go over, today.

 

I’m joined today by special guest Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage to talk about a few hot topics relating to mortgage lending and real estate in 2018.

We’re focusing on three subjects, specifically.


  
    Tax reform. Right now, tax reform is a huge topic in San Diego. With property tax deductions capped at $10,000 and mortgage interest deductions capped at $750,000, many people are concerned. As a result, Todd tells me that he’s been receiving a lot of calls about refinancing. Still, Todd doesn’t believe tax reform will slow down the market. He says people still need to buy homes, so they shouldn’t let these changes prevent them from doing so.
  
  
    Paying points. Todd says people need to start talking about paying points, since points are still tax deductible. If you’re paying points, you can actually buy down your interest rate to eventually earn a better one. You can also deduct points on a refinance, as well, if you deduct over the lifetime of the loan. A lot of mortgage lenders are scared to sell points because they aren’t used to doing so, but Todd has been doing this for the last 20 years.
  
  
    Niche programs. According to Todd, 2018 will be the “year of the niche.” There are already a number of diverse programs available in today’s market. Whatever a buyer’s circumstances may be, there is likely a program out there to suit their needs.
  


“People still need to buy homes, so they shouldn’t let tax reform prevent them from doing so.”

If you are looking for more mortgage information and want to get in touch with Todd, you can give him a call at (858) 775-8958 or email him at tpianin@rpm-mtg.com.

Todd Pianin, Regional Manager NMLS# 304014LendUS, LLC dba RPM Mortgage NMLS #1938 - Licensed by the Department of Business Oversight under the CA Residential Mortgage Lending Act. Equal Housing Opportunity.

And as always, if you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/3+Hot+Lending+Topics+for+2018.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/3+Hot+Lending+Topics+for+2018.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s going on in the lending world right now in San Diego? There are three main topics I’d like to go over, today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s going on in the lending world right now in San Diego? There are three main topics I’d like to go over, today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers & Sellers Can Expect in These Unusual Times</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-buyers-sellers-can-expect-in-these-unusual-times.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-02 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/What+Buyers+%26+Sellers+Can+Expect+in+These+Unusual+Times.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here&rsquo;s my recent conversation with Tawnie Vargas of Oakwood Escrow on the nature of changes to our respective industries.

If you’re a potential buyer or seller or are in the middle of a real estate transaction right now, uncertainty lingers. The good news, however, is that the real estate business, with all of its associated industries, is still moving along. Tawnie Vargas of Oakwood Escrow joined me to discuss the need for patience—there will be delays—and the importance of understanding that this situation is nowhere near the 2008 crisis.

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:

1:10 - Are escrow companies even up and running? What does the business look like now?2:19 - How is Oakwood keeping clients safe and still getting the job done?4:08 - How buyers and sellers can prepare for virtual escrows and other changes4:58 - We’re not in a recession; this is not like 20086:36 - The need for collective patience7:35 - The importance of open communication in these times8:58 - Wrapping things up

Give Tawnie a call at (951) 704-6116, send her an email at tvargas@oakwoodescrow.com, or visit Oakwood Escrow's website if you have any escrow-related questions.

If you have any questions about the real estate market, or if you’re interested in buying or selling a home soon but aren’t sure how to proceed in these times, reach out to us. We’re always here to help and look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/What+Buyers+%26+Sellers+Can+Expect+in+These+Unusual+Times.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/What+Buyers+%26+Sellers+Can+Expect+in+These+Unusual+Times.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s my Monday, March 30, conversation with Tawnie Vargas of Oakwood Escrow on the nature of changes to our respective industries.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s my Monday, March 30, conversation with Tawnie Vargas of Oakwood Escrow on the nature of changes to our respective industries.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Be a Contingent Buyer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-be-a-contingent-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Be+a+Contingent+Buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I&rsquo;m sharing three ways you can be a contingent homebuyer.

Are you considering purchasing a home this year but have one to sell first? You’re in luck—today I’m discussing how to be a contingent buyer. Being a contingent buyer means that an offer on a new house has been made and the seller has accepted it, but that the final sale is contingent upon certain criteria that have to be met.

Here are the top three ways to become a contingent buyer:

1. Prep the home for sale. Have everything prepared in your home while you’re looking for your next one. Typically we sit down and come up with an action plan of exactly how we help you move, we help prep your house, take photos, etc. This way we can tell the seller of your next property that you’re ready to move. The day after your offer is accepted on a new home, your current house goes up for sale, so the two processes move simultaneously. This is the most common way to be a contingent buyer, and it’s also the most seamless.

2. Sell your home and rent it back. You can sell your property without being a contingent seller, then rent it back for a short time. Generally, we see people renting their homes back for 30 to 60 days. This way you aren’t waiting for your house to sell before you buy the new home, because you’ve already sold it. This commonly works for people who don’t need to move into a new home right away. If the house you want exists in the market, it’s easy to use this strategy.

“Not every option is right for everyone.”

3. Store your things after you sell. This is a short-term situation where you would sell your property, move out, (and people like that you’re able to do this quickly), your items will be put into storage, we would find a short-term rental for you, and then you buy and move into your next home. This allows you to make non-contingent house purchases. You’ll win by getting a better deal.

Not every option is right for everyone. Every person and situation is different. We would build a custom plan explaining how the strategy would work for you, then we’d work from that plan. This is the ideal way to be successful as a contingent buyer.

If we can help you sell your home and buy another this year, we would love for you to reach out to us by phone or email. We look forward to assisting you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Be+a+Contingent+Buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Be+a+Contingent+Buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m sharing three ways you can be a contingent homebuyer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m sharing three ways you can be a contingent homebuyer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Homeowner Association Questions</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/homeowner-association-questions.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-02 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Homeowner+Association+Questions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I&rsquo;m sharing the four main things you should consider when thinking about moving into an HOA neighborhood.

Are you looking to buy a home or condo in a community with a homeowner’s association? When we’re showing houses, we’re frequently asked about the pros and cons of living in an HOA community. Today we’ll go over the four main things to look into when you’re considering a home in an HOA neighborhood.

1. Rules and regulations. This is the most essential point in this list. These can be anything from what kind of pets you can own, the rental restrictions, what colors you can paint your house, and so on. This is the first thing to consider when buying in an HOA community.

2. Financial security. This one is commonly overlooked. Even though you may love a community, take a look at the HOA’s financial stability to make sure that if an unanticipated issue that the HOA is responsible for arises, they have the capability to handle it. Otherwise, you’ll be paying for it.

“Take a look at the HOA’s financial stability.”

3. What’s included. There are all types of complexes out there, and they all have a unique set of rules. Things like water, sewage, and trash could be included in the HOA, but sometimes they aren’t. Do they take care of the front yard, roof, and common area maintenance?

4. Fees. Is this a community in which the fees continually go up year after year? Do they have large expenses coming up that you may have to help pay? HOA documents give you all the information discussed in previous meetings and what will come up in the next ones.

These are the top four things to look into if you’re considering moving into an HOA neighborhood or community. If we can be of help to you in navigating the world of HOAs, or if you have any other questions, please give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Homeowner+Association+Questions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Homeowner+Association+Questions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m sharing the four main things you should consider when thinking about moving into an HOA neighborhood.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m sharing the four main things you should consider when thinking about moving into an HOA neighborhood.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Mistakes to Avoid When Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-mistakes-to-avoid-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-06 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/4+Mistakes+to+Avoid+When+Selling+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I&rsquo;m sharing four mistakes home sellers often make when selling their homes. Don&rsquo;t do these four things!

Today we’re discussing the four massive mistakes we see home sellers make when it comes time to sell their home:

1. Assuming you will get top dollar. If you assume you will receive top dollar for your home because your neighbor did, this isn’t necessarily the case. Every home is unique; whether it’s the finishes, the lot, the view, or the condition of the home, they all make a substantial difference in the value. Also, every home requires distinct marketing and a slightly different technique to sell it. The key to receiving top dollar for your home is knowing who your buyer is and knowing where to price it.

2. Assuming the price is everything. Price is important, but it isn’t everything. Homes commonly sell for top dollar in the first two to four weeks. If not, they’re perhaps slightly overpriced. The price of the home needs to be just right. The margins in home pricing these days are razor thin. If a home is slightly overpriced, it can be on the market four or five months later.

“Price is important, but it isn’t everything.”

3. Not using professional photography. Professional photography in 2019 is essential. Not using professional photography is the first way to ensure your home fails to sell. Today people scroll Instagram and Facebook and buy items because the photography caught their eye. When people are scrolling their phones or tablets, we want your home to attract their attention.

4. Not addressing simple repairs or curb appeal. Many times we walk into a home that is simply not ready to be sold. Prepping for sale could be as straightforward as a deep cleaning or fresh wood chips and flowers in the yard. Often we notice an old door handle is the first impression because it’s the first thing buyers see when they walk up to the house. Frequently, investing between $500 and $1,000 can make a massive difference when it comes time to sell. We also see this with repairs: A few hundred dollars can make a huge difference.

Look at the big picture. No one wants to spend more money than necessary. If you would like a consultation on your home for how to get it sold for top dollar, we’d love to sit down and earn the opportunity. If you have any questions please contact us by phone or email. We look forward to speaking with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/4+Mistakes+to+Avoid+When+Selling+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/4+Mistakes+to+Avoid+When+Selling+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m sharing four mistakes home sellers often make when selling their homes. Don’t do these four things!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m sharing four mistakes home sellers often make when selling their homes. Don’t do these four things!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We’re Grateful for Your Support</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-grateful-for-your-support.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-21 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Were+Grateful+for+Your+Support.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Thank you for letting us help you achieve your real estate goals.

For today’s video, I want to thank you for continuing to support my team and me year after year as we grow in our real estate journey. For subscribing to our video blog and referring wonderful clients to us, we’re expressing our gratitude to you.

I know there are a ton of options out there to help you reach your real estate goals, so it means a lot that you trust us to do this. This year has been extraordinary for us, and we’re excited for 2020, but as we wind down for the holidays, we’re thankful for our friends, family, and the opportunities we’ve been given. On that note, I’ve invited a few team members to join me today to share what they’re grateful for.

Remember, we’re always ready to help you no matter what your real estate goals are, so don’t hesitate to call or email us anytime. Happy Thanksgiving!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Were+Grateful+for+Your+Support.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Were+Grateful+for+Your+Support.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Thank you for letting us help you achieve your real estate goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Thank you for letting us help you achieve your real estate goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Autumn and Winter Markets in San Diego</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/autumn-and-winter-markets-in-san-diego.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-05 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Autumn+and+Winter+Markets+in+San+Diego.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I&rsquo;m sharing all the newest information about our San Diego real estate markets.

 

As you may have heard recently, the market is broadly seeing a modest increase from last year to this year. We’re noticing open houses are exceedingly busy. In fact, we welcomed over 200 people at our last open house! We’re seeing a lot of energy return to the market, and I foresee this will continue through the winter months as long as interest rates stay where they are.

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:

0:20 - Why we’re seeing an increase in the market

1:35 - Why homeowners are investing more money into their homes

2:40 - Why many need to sell their home before they buy another

4:05 - Investing properly

5:35 - Wrapping up

If you have any questions about real estate, pick up the phone and call me at (858) 345-9995 or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Autumn+and+Winter+Markets+in+San+Diego.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Autumn+and+Winter+Markets+in+San+Diego.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m sharing all the newest information about our San Diego real estate markets.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m sharing all the newest information about our San Diego real estate markets.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will 2019 Be the Year of the Late Selling Season?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-2019-be-the-year-of-the-late-selling-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-19 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Will+2019+Be+the+Year+of+the+Late+Selling+Season_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In 2019, a late-year sale is actually a great idea, and today I&rsquo;ll explain why.

 

If you’ve been thinking of selling your home this year but fear it may be too late, think again. The home-selling season is far from over. In fact, selling later in the year in 2019 may actually work to your advantage.

Typically in San Diego, the peak of the market is usually around mid-to-late June—but because of the (comparatively) high interest rates we saw at the end of 2018 and the excess inventory that marked the beginning of 2019, many people decided to hold off on making a move. This lack of activity was likely also due to pre-election jitters, as studies show that the real estate market tends to slow when a presidential election is on the horizon.

However, now that interest rates are at all-time lows, buyer demand has really ramped up. Many sellers have also taken this opportunity to relist properties that failed to sell earlier in the year. We haven’t seen this kind of late-year resurgence for some time.

“The bottom line is that anyone thinking of selling should think about entering the market soon.”

The bottom line is that anyone thinking of selling should think about entering the market soon. Current conditions will likely help you to sell quickly and for top dollar, but they won’t last forever.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want to have a conversation with our team about your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Will+2019+Be+the+Year+of+the+Late+Selling+Season_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Will+2019+Be+the+Year+of+the+Late+Selling+Season_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In 2019, a late-year sale is actually a great idea, and today I’ll explain why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In 2019, a late-year sale is actually a great idea, and today I’ll explain why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy Now or Wait?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-now-or-wait.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Should+You+Buy+Now+or+Wait_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you&rsquo;ve been wondering whether now is the time to buy, today&rsquo;s message is for you.

 

If you’re thinking of buying a home this year but aren’t sure whether the timing is right, this message will help you decide whether moving forward with a home search is right for you.

For one thing, the question of whether 2019 is a good year to buy a home doesn’t have a one-size-fits-all answer. It really depends on your personal circumstances. Therefore, understanding what’s happening in our market right now will definitely allow you to make an educated choice.

First, there aren’t enough homes on our market today to satisfy the high buyer demand our sub-4% interest rates has generated.

“Rates are low, homes are affordable, and there are plenty of great properties available if you know where to look.”

And as a result of this high demand, buyers have split into two general demographics: those looking for move-in ready properties and those willing to take a chance on fixer-uppers. What many buyers in the first category might not realize is that not all of these fixer-uppers are as shabby as they think. In fact, some have great potential that could easily be drawn out with just a few cosmetic upgrades.

But don’t let this scare you. Although buyers have come out in droves, prices haven’t shot up the way you might expect. Rather, they’ve remained fairly flat. This gives buyers a little bit of extra leverage and sellers a higher incentive to be open to negotiation.

The bottom line is that now is the time to take advantage. Rates are low, homes are affordable, and there are plenty of great properties available if you know where to look. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Should+You+Buy+Now+or+Wait_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Should+You+Buy+Now+or+Wait_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’ve been wondering whether now is the time to buy, today’s message is for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’ve been wondering whether now is the time to buy, today’s message is for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Home Sellers: These Steps Will Be the Key to Your Success</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/home-sellers-these-steps-will-be-the-key-to-your-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Home+Sellers-+These+Steps+Will+Be+the+Key+to+Your+Success.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does it take to succeed in today&rsquo;s San Diego area market? Find out with this quick message.

 

A lot of people are wondering what’s happening right now in our San Diego area market and how they can make the most of these current conditions, so today, we’ll get to the bottom of things with a quick update.

For one thing, inventory is climbing each month, as is the average number of days homes are spending on the market. For detached homes, the average days homes spend on the market has risen 17% year over year. The average number of days it takes condos to sell, meanwhile, has gone up 30% over that same period.

Part of the reason for this slowdown is that many of the new listings being put up for sale aren’t exactly up to par. There are a lot of less-than-desirable properties being listed these days, and buyers just aren’t interested in pursuing those kinds of homes.

Therefore, pre-listing preparations (like cleaning, decluttering, and staging) are imperative to sellers’ success.

“The most important step you can take to secure your success as a seller is to hire an experienced agent.”

Instead of investing in minor upgrades, like replacing carpet, too many sellers are opting to dramatically reduce their sales price if they do happen to find an interested buyer. If these sellers simply made the necessary upgrades before listing, they wouldn’t have to reduce their price at all. It’s important to focus on your bottom line above all else when it comes time to prepare your home for the market.

On that note, proper pricing is also key to succeeding in our current market. Homes priced at, or even slightly below, fair market value tend to attract the most buyers.

However, the absolute most important step you can take to secure your success as a seller is to hire an experienced agent. Even in today’s digital age, where seemingly endless information is at our fingertips, having a professional to guide you through the real estate process is still essential.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious how the Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Team can help you meet your goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Home+Sellers-+These+Steps+Will+Be+the+Key+to+Your+Success.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Home+Sellers-+These+Steps+Will+Be+the+Key+to+Your+Success.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What does it take to succeed in today’s San Diego area market? Find out with this quick message.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What does it take to succeed in today’s San Diego area market? Find out with this quick message.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Closing Costs to Be Aware of Before Buying a Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-closing-costs-to-be-aware-of-before-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-20 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+5+Closing+Costs+to+Be+Aware+of+Before+Buying+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you&rsquo;re a homebuyer, there are several closing costs you need to be prepared for in addition to your down payment.

 

When it comes time to close on your next property, there are five closing costs you need to be prepared for:

1. Escrow fees. Being in escrow means you’re in an arrangement where a neutral third party helps exchange documents and money so that own the home free and clear once the transaction is complete. This is typically one of the larger closing costs you’ll have to cover.

2. Title fees. If you’re getting a loan or transferring properties, the seller pays the majority of these, and you only have to pay a small amount to ensure that the title is exchanged without issue.

3. Lender fees. Various lender fees are built into all mortgage loans—some of which are included in the financing, while others are paid up front. In any case, make sure you go over these fees with your lender.

“Various lender fees are built into all mortgage loans.”

4. Prepaid fees. These can include taxes, insurance costs, and interest payments.

5. The supplemental tax bill. This might not come up at the closing table, but you may get a bill in the mail three months later stating that you owe supplemental tax. What does this mean? Basically, if you buy a home at a certain price but it sold previously for a lesser amount, you have to pay whatever the difference is in terms of property tax.

If you need help buying your next home or you have any other real estate needs I can help you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+5+Closing+Costs+to+Be+Aware+of+Before+Buying+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+5+Closing+Costs+to+Be+Aware+of+Before+Buying+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a homebuyer, there are several closing costs you need to be prepared for in addition to your down payment.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a homebuyer, there are several closing costs you need to be prepared for in addition to your down payment.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Become Debt-Free Faster?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-become-debt-free-faster.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+Do+You+Become+Debt-Free+Faster_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you looking to slay the mortgage monster by paying your mortgage down faster so you can own your home free and clear? Well, you&rsquo;re in luck!

 

How can you pay down your mortgage faster so that you can own your home debt-free? Today I’ll share two great ideas you should look into when it comes time to purchase your next home or refinance your current one:

1. Make one extra payment every year. Did you know that by making one extra payment on your 30-year mortgage every single year, you could actually pay off your mortgage seven years faster? If you do this, you’ll also end up paying a lot less in interest over that time.

“Did you know that on a $500,000 house, you could save almost $160,000 on interest payments by switching from a 30-year to a 15-year mortgage?”

2. Make sure you know the difference between a 30-year mortgage and a 15-year mortgage. Many will typically go for a 30-year mortgage because they think they’ll be in the house long-term, but did you know that on a $500,000 house, you could save almost $160,000 on interest payments by switching from a 30-year to a 15-year mortgage? Now, if you do this, the monthly payments will be a little bit higher, but at the end of the day, you could save hundreds of thousands of dollars that could be money going right back into your pocket.

If we can help connect you to one of our trusted lenders to help you slay the mortgage monster or if you have any questions, you should absolutely feel free to reach out to my team. We’d love to help you out. We hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+Do+You+Become+Debt-Free+Faster_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+Do+You+Become+Debt-Free+Faster_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you looking to slay the mortgage monster by paying your mortgage down faster so you can own your home free and clear? Well, you’re in luck!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you looking to slay the mortgage monster by paying your mortgage down faster so you can own your home free and clear? Well, you’re in luck!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Get the Most Money for Your Home When It Comes Time to Sell?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-get-the-most-money-for-your-home-when-it-comes-time-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-19 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+Can+You+Get+the+Most+Money+for+Your+Home+When+It+Comes+Time+to+Sell_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To make your home sell quickly and for top dollar once it hits the market, you need to focus on preparation, price, and the pro you use.

 

What’s the key to winning when it comes time to sell? In other words, how can you sell for the most money in the shortest amount of time?

It all boils down to three factors: preparation, price, and the pro who helps you win.  

1. Preparation. Oftentimes, we’ll see beautiful homes on the market that, regardless, fail to really capture buyers’ interest because their sellers didn’t spend any money on them. What can you do to prepare your home so this doesn’t happen to you? 

First, make sure it gives a great first impression. Curb appeal goes a long way in this regard, and that appeal has to stretch from the curb all the way to the front door, so freshen up your front yard’s landscaping and make your front door look like something someone wants to come home to. 

On the inside, consider adding a fresh coat of paint—it’s a very minimal expense that can yield thousands of dollars on your return, and you don’t necessarily have to paint the entire interior. Also, make sure your faucets and sinks are clean, and if they need to be replaced, replace them. Low-cost items like these can also yield a large return when it comes time to sell. 

Next, look at your electrical fixtures. Installing just a few ceiling-mounted lights can dramatically change the look and feel of your home.

“Having a professional real estate agent help you navigate the steps of the home selling process is incredibly important.”

2. Price. Nowadays, this matters more than anything in terms of getting your home sold. The only homes that are getting multiple offers these days are those that are brand new, extremely renovated, or heavily discounted because there’s something wrong with them. Therefore, if you list your home at a higher price than what it’s really worth, it will likely sell for less than its actual market value. 

If you list it at market value, on the other hand, you’ll have a much better chance at selling over list price and in a shorter amount of time. 

3. The pro you use. There’s so much competition in the market right now, and having a professional real estate agent help you navigate the steps of the home selling process is incredibly important. Make sure you ask your agent the tough questions and inquire what their plan is to get your home sold. They should have a sensible plan with the proper marketing that will draw dramatic attention to your listing. 

If you have any questions about this topic or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+Can+You+Get+the+Most+Money+for+Your+Home+When+It+Comes+Time+to+Sell_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+Can+You+Get+the+Most+Money+for+Your+Home+When+It+Comes+Time+to+Sell_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>To make your home sell quickly and for top dollar once it hits the market, you need to focus on preparation, price, and the pro you use.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>To make your home sell quickly and for top dollar once it hits the market, you need to focus on preparation, price, and the pro you use.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening in San Diego's Spring Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-san-diegos-spring-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+What's+Happening+in+San+Diego's+Spring+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are three main trends to take note of if you plan on buying or selling soon in our San Diego market, and I&rsquo;d like to share these trends with you today.

 

Today more than ever, people approach me to ask about the state of our San Diego market. To answer this common question, I’d like to share three trends I’ve noticed this spring: 

1. Interest rates have dropped. Now that interest rates have dipped down to the mid-4% range, buyers once again have the opportunity to enjoy historically low rates. This is exciting for sellers, too, as this boost in affordability has also fostered increased demand. 

2. Inventory is up. There are almost 20% more homes listed on the market than we had at this time in 2018. This gives buyers a greater level of choice, meaning you don’t have to settle for a mediocre (yet overpriced) home. Sellers, meanwhile, must understand that appropriate pricing will be key in light of this trend. 

3. Appreciation is slowing down. We’ve seen high single- and double-digit appreciation rates for some time now, but it’s starting to look as though 2019 will see prices rise much less dramatically. What does this mean for you? If you’re a buyer, it means that there will be more opportunities for leverage in the market. For sellers, it means that the days of receiving a dozen or more offers on a listing may soon be over. It doesn’t mean, though, that you don’t still have the chance to earn top dollar. With the right marketing and the right agent by your side, you can still get a great deal.

“The bottom line is that buyers and sellers alike have a window of opportunity before them right now, but one that won’t last forever.”

The bottom line is that buyers and sellers alike have a window of opportunity before them right now, but one that won’t last forever. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+What's+Happening+in+San+Diego's+Spring+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+What's+Happening+in+San+Diego's+Spring+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are three main trends to take note of if you plan on buying or selling soon in our San Diego market, and I’d like to share these trends with you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are three main trends to take note of if you plan on buying or selling soon in our San Diego market, and I’d like to share these trends with you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Home Staging Will Help You Sell for Top Dollar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-home-staging-will-help-you-sell-for-top-dollar.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-15 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Why+Home+Staging+Will+Help+You+Sell+for+Top+Dollar.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Staging a home is important, and here&rsquo;s how to do it.

 

We’re here today at the BlueGrape Staging warehouse facility, where they have all kinds of amazing things that are used to help homes come to life. We’re joined by owner and design expert Pramiti Bhargava, who will help us understand why home staging is so important for making a top-dollar sale.

Every home needs to be presented correctly, whether it’s occupied or vacant. Every buyer who walks in wants to have a connection with the house before they make an offer—they want to see themselves living there. You need to depersonalize your home to give a blank slate to potential buyers. For example, pictures of your family can distract buyers from viewing the actual features of a home.

Sometimes, homes don’t have the correct furniture setup. There are two important things to consider: layout and scale. A buyer needs to walk into a certain flow of traffic, but furniture can detract from this. A huge sectional can make a room seem half its size, but buyers want a home that seems big and open. Also, out-of-date furniture can make your home seem, well, out of date. You’re selling to today’s buyers—not buyers in the 1960s.

“Every buyer who walks in wants to have a connection with the house before they make an offer.”

Updating your decor and being on-trend helps your home fetch the best price. When people see lighter, neutral furniture, they can better appreciate the character and strength of the house. After all, they aren’t buying the furniture; they’re buying the house. Creating a consistent design from room to room is a good way to wow buyers.

As we’re seeing more inventory in our market, it’s more important than ever to make sure your home is properly staged. These tips will help you stand out from the crowd and ensure you sell your home for top dollar. To get a staging consultation, reach out to Pramiti through her website at BlueGrapeStaging.com or call (858) 652-3007.

If you have any other questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.

Pramiti BhargavaBlueGrape Staging7485 Trade St. BSan Diego, CA 92121(858) 652-3007pramiti@bluegrape.usbluegrapestaging.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Why+Home+Staging+Will+Help+You+Sell+for+Top+Dollar.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Why+Home+Staging+Will+Help+You+Sell+for+Top+Dollar.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Staging a home is important, and here’s how to do it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Staging a home is important, and here’s how to do it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>These 4 Color Palettes Will Dominate Design Trends in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/these-4-color-palettes-will-dominate-design-trends-in-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-21 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+These+4+Color+Palettes+Will+Dominate+Design+Trends+in+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Which four color palettes are about to dominate design trends in the new year? Find out in today&rsquo;s message.

 

Design expert Pramiti Bhargava of BlueGrape Staging has joined us again today to discuss what color trends we can expect in the new year.

There are four main palettes Pramiti predicts will take the place of the greys and whites that dominated designs in 2018.

First off, earthy tones are about to have a major moment, with warm colors like terra cotta likely to appear more frequently as design accents in the coming months.

Metallics, too, are going to be big and will likely often be paired with black. This trend will most likely appear in kitchens and bathrooms, where bronze, gold, and chrome hardware is becoming more common once more.

The third upcoming trend Pramiti mentioned is one of her personal favorites: the increasing use of the color green. From mint to emerald, every shade of this color is being more frequently incorporated into home design as of late.

“It will be interesting to see how these trends emerge throughout 2019.”

Last, but not least, Pramiti and I touched on one of my own go-to colors: navy blue. Though this particular shade is not new to popular design, it has shown to be a long-standing classic. “It is almost like a neutral,” says Pramiti, citing the color’s calming effect.

Ultimately, there are a lot of exciting trends on the horizon. It will be interesting to see how these trends emerge throughout 2019.

To learn more about these trends, or about home design in general, visit bluegrapestaging.com.

And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Pramiti BhargavaBlueGrape Staging7485 Trade St. BSan Diego, CA 92121(858) 652-3007pramiti@bluegrape.usbluegrapestaging.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+These+4+Color+Palettes+Will+Dominate+Design+Trends+in+2019.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+-+These+4+Color+Palettes+Will+Dominate+Design+Trends+in+2019.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Which four color palettes are about to dominate design trends in the new year? Find out in today’s message.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Which four color palettes are about to dominate design trends in the new year? Find out in today’s message.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hottest Design Trends in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/hottest-design-trends-in-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Hottest+Design+Trends+in+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you looking for the hottest design trends and homes going into 2019? Well, you&rsquo;re in luck&mdash;today, Pramiti Bhargava from Bluegrape Staging is here to provide you with the latest details you need to know.

 

Today we are honored and fortunate to have one of our wonderful staging and design partners with us: Pramiti Bhargava, owner and co-founder of Bluegrape Staging, a company that focuses on the business of real estate staging. Pramiti is here to tell us about the hottest design trends to expect for 2019:

1. Bolder options in tile and kitchen designs. So far, monochromatic tiles in colors like white have been popular, but Pramiti believes that in 2019, we’ll see bolder choices in terms of graphics. In regards to kitchen styles, we have also been accustomed to monochromatic choices, like all-white and all-gray palettes. 2019 will show us more two-toned drama, such as with lighter countertops and darker cabinetry.

2. Organic and recycled materials. Pramiti has noticed that jute, a type of recyclable material like cotton, is being used not just in terms of furniture and accessories, but also in wallpaper, rugs, and other home elements. Glass is another material to watch out for; she’s even seen people using recycled glass for countertops. The innovated and reinvented use of sustainable materials will be very en vogue in the coming year.

3. Gold and metallic finishes for handles, knobs, and faucets. These have been popular this year, and will remain so, with a few additions. As well as metallic gold finishes, we’ll see copper, brass, and bronze. We’ll see gold and matte gold accents, as well. This will carry over into wallpaper, accents, accessories, artwork, and more.

“The innovated and reinvented use of sustainable materials will be very en vogue in the coming year.”

4. Wallpaper will make a comeback. This might scare some people who imagine wallpaper going up all through the house, but that’s not how it’s going to be; we’ll see wallpaper on accent walls in hallways, bathrooms, and so on.

5. Globally inspired patterns and colors will be huge. Patterns derived from international cultures, such as those globally inspired from Morocco and Turkey, will likely surge in popularity come 2019. There is so much color and vibrance to take advantage of; colors like navy, bronze, mustard, and terra cotta will probably make their way to accent walls, wallpaper, and other decorative elements.

If you’re looking to make a change or adjust the aesthetic of your own home based on the hottest trends in the market, contact Pramiti Bhargava at (858) 652-3007, email pramiti@bluegrape.us, or visit their website. They work with both home sellers in the market and with new construction homes, striving to bring homes to life, so that when buyers walk into a home, they’ll form an emotional connection with the property.

For any other questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to the Sean Zanganeh Real Estate Team. We’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Hottest+Design+Trends+in+2019.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Hottest+Design+Trends+in+2019.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you looking for the hottest design trends and homes going into 2019?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you looking for the hottest design trends and homes going into 2019?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Top 3 Home Inspection Discoveries</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-home-inspection-discoveries.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-10 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+The+3+Main+Kinds+of+Issues+Home+Inspections+Can+Identify.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are three primary kinds of issues covered in the home inspection process. Let&rsquo;s review what they are.

 

Home inspections are an essential step in the real estate process. Assuming no major issues are uncovered, they can provide buyers with peace of mind before closing. But buyers who are about to go through this process are often curious about what to expect.

In general terms, there are three primary kinds of issues home inspections are meant to identify, and we’ll be reviewing each of them today.

1. Safety. Some of the most important issues an inspection may uncover are those that could pose a real danger to people occupying the home. Problems with the home’s electrical or plumbing systems and broken door locks are just two examples of such issues. Anything that renders a property unsafe must be identified and resolved.

2. Structural. All of the structural components of a home, such as its foundation and roof, should be in good, sound condition.

3. Mechanical. Air conditioning units, water heaters, and other mechanical components of the home should be in good working order before you move in. Preemptively assessing these units during an inspection will help save you from needing to fix them after closing.

“Anything that renders a property unsafe must be identified and resolved.”

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+The+3+Main+Kinds+of+Issues+Home+Inspections+Can+Identify.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+The+3+Main+Kinds+of+Issues+Home+Inspections+Can+Identify.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are three primary kinds of issues covered in the home inspection process. Let’s review what they are.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are three primary kinds of issues covered in the home inspection process. Let’s review what they are.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy a House Before You Turn 30</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-a-house-before-you-turn-30.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-24 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+to+Buy+a+House+Before+You+Turn+30.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to explain how you can buy a home in your 20s to help you build wealth in your 30s.

 

So you’re in your 20s and you want to buy your first home. Contrary to what some believe, millennials are completely capable of purchasing homes by following a few key steps. So if you’re a 20-something looking to buy a home before you turn 30, simply follow these tips.

The first thing you need to do is understand your finances. What are you making now and what do you think you’ll make in the next 24 months? Look at those numbers to find out when the right time is for you to buy. Many people think that you need to save a lot of money to buy a house, but this isn’t entirely true. There are plenty of options to buy homes for as little as 5%, 3%, 1% or even 0% down, and we would love to help you understand those options.

The next thing to do is meet with a lender. Too many people have no idea that they qualify for a home and have been paying rent because they don’t know any better. Actually sitting down at a meeting with a lender to discuss your options is a huge benefit because then you know exactly what you qualify for. If you don’t like the amount, you can also set up a goal with the lender to achieve so you can buy something later.

Have a great real estate agent. Many 20-somethings looking to buy are going to be buying in price points that are heavily impacted in today’s market. If you think it’s a good deal, chances are other people do as well. To counter that, you have to work with an agent who understands how to quickly analyze a deal to see if it’s worth taking the next step or if it’s a big waste of time.

“You have to work with an agent who understands how to quickly analyze a deal to see if it’s worth taking the next step or if it’s a big waste of time.”

With these tips in mind, we also want to give you a few ideas on how to think about owning a home in your 20s:

Think of it as an investment property. It’s perfectly fine to own a home for yourself, but a lot of people also look at it from an investment perspective where you buy a property to help you accumulate wealth in your 20s for a family home later. Basically, you want to find a property to rent out where the rent can provide you with income in the near and long-term future.

Try house hacking. This means that you’re buying a property with multiple units where you live in one and then rent out the others, which can help subsidize housing costs. Some young people are even able to profit by purchasing a multiple unit home.

Live with family or friends. As long as you have a written agreement with an exit clause that makes sense for both of you, you can partner with family and friends. I’ve even seen people ask for money to buy a property to start their real estate portfolio and by their mid-30s, they have built a lot of wealth.

If you have any questions about buying in your 20s, please feel free to reach out to me. I would be happy to speak with you about building your wealth for your future.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+to+Buy+a+House+Before+You+Turn+30.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+to+Buy+a+House+Before+You+Turn+30.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to explain how you can buy a home in your 20s to help you build wealth in your 30s.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to explain how you can buy a home in your 20s to help you build wealth in your 30s.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Keys to Pricing Your Home Correctly?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-keys-to-pricing-your-home-correctly.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+to+price+your+home+in+today%2527s+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Pricing your home properly is one of the keys to getting it sold quickly and for top dollar. Here are a few reasons why.

&nbsp;

If you’re thinking of listing your home in the near future but aren’t quite sure how to price it in this changing market, we’ve got some great tips to share with you. 

At the beginning of this year, we had roughly 4,000 homes on the market. At the peak of the summer market, we had somewhere between 7,500 and 7,800 homes. This is a large increase in inventory, which makes pricing your home that much more important.

To know if this increase of inventory makes a difference for you in your community, we have to look at comparable sales. When you are competing against multiple homes, you have to price it right in order to sell quickly and for top dollar.

“The quality of the agent you choose and the quality of their marketing is essential to your success.”

If there are a lot of homes for sale in the area, can you be the most expensive home on the market? Maybe, maybe not. We like our clients to take a close look at the other homes for sale in their market so they can really compare the features and benefits of those homes to their own. Looking at the most recently sold homes in the area and their prices will assist you in finding a price that makes sense.

Finally, marketing is of the utmost importance. The quality of the agent you choose and the quality of their marketing plan will make the difference between you selling in a few weeks vs. selling in a few months. We focus on the marketing that helps you win in the shortest amount of time, while also pricing the home at a level that is attractive to you as a home seller.

If you have any more questions about pricing your home or about anything else related to real estate, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+to+price+your+home+in+today%2527s+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+How+to+price+your+home+in+today%2527s+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Pricing your home properly is one of the keys to getting it sold quickly and for top dollar. Here are a few reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Pricing your home properly is one of the keys to getting it sold quickly and for top dollar. Here are a few reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Propositions 60 and 90 Can Help You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-propositions-60-and-90-can-help-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-06 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Relief+for+Homeowners+Age+55+and+Older.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you heard about Propositions 60 and 90? If you&rsquo;re 55 or older, you need to know about how they can help you save on your taxes.

 

Are you 55 or older and want to keep your tax bases? If so, we’ve got some great information for you today. Our lovely guests, Shawn and Alix from Fidelity Title, are joining us to talk about Propositions 60 and 90 and why they’re important to you.

Propositions 60 and 90 are constitutional amendments in California that allow tax relief for a homeowner who is 55 years of age or older. This allows them to transfer that tax base to another property. There are some requirements you need to meet in order to qualify for these. Here are the most important:


  Either you or your spouse has to be 55 or older.
  The home has to be your principal residence.
  When you’re making the transfer, it has to be to a property that is of equal or lower market value.
  You must find the replacement property within two years of selling your current home.


“There could be some interesting changes coming to this amendment.”

There are some potential upgrades coming to Propositions 60 and 90 as well. They aren’t on the ballot in California yet, but signatures are being collected right now. If these amendments pass, they open up the benefits to all of San Diego County and will allow homeowners to use them more than once. Currently, you can only transfer the tax base once. Another big change could allow you to transfer your tax base to a home that’s worth more instead of being at equal or lesser value.

If something like this happens in the near future, that would open up the market to a ton of buyers in the area. If you want more information about how you can qualify for Propositions 60 and 90, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you and talk to you more about how you can benefit from the San Diego real estate market right now.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Relief+for+Homeowners+Age+55+and+Older.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/San+Diego%252C+CA+Real+Estate+-+Relief+for+Homeowners+Age+55+and+Older.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you heard about Prop 60 & 90? If you’re 55 or older, you need to know about how it can help you save on your taxes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you heard about Prop 60 & 90? If you’re 55 or older, you need to know about how it can help you save on your taxes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Convert Covered Patios Into Additional Living Space</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-convert-covered-patios-into-additional-living-space.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-25 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Convert+Covered+Patios+Into+Additional+Living+Space.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Can you convert a covered patio into additional living space? Today we&rsquo;ll be discussing this topic with a local expert.

 

Do you have a patio or outdoor area that you want to convert into an additional living space? If so, we’ve got a few tips and tricks for how you can do so.

Joining us to help cover this topic is Ian Scattergood of Permit Pro Consultants.

So how can someone go about adding additional space to their home with an enclosed patio? According to Ian, the first thing to consider is whether the space meets the floor area ratio (or FAR) and the lot coverage. Once this is confirmed, plans can be drawn, the permit can be issued, and the homeowner can proceed with converting the space into additional square footage or a second rentable unit.

It’s important to realize, though, that the process varies when it comes to older structures. What then must be done to ensure older structures can qualify as additional living space?

“Qualifying older structures as additional living space mostly comes down to meeting specific city or county zone ordinances.”

Ian says it mostly comes down to meeting specific city or county zone ordinances. If everything checks out under those ordinances, then the same process as before can be carried out to qualify the space.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to call Ian at (619) 579-0088 or email him at ian@permitprosd.com.

And, as always, if you have any questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.

Ian ScattergoodPermit Pro Consultants(619) 579-0088ian@permitprosd.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Convert+Covered+Patios+Into+Additional+Living+Space.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/How+to+Convert+Covered+Patios+Into+Additional+Living+Space.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Can you convert a covered patio into additional living space? Today we’ll be discussing this topic with a local expert.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Can you convert a covered patio into additional living space? Today we’ll be discussing this topic with a local expert.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Really Know Who Owns the Property?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-you-really-know-who-owns-the-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Do+You+Really+Know+Who+Owns+the+Property%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The issue of ownership is very important when it comes time to list a home. Today we will discuss a few key scenarios about listing after ownership-related complications arise.

 

Are you considering selling your home but don’t really know who owns the house? Well today I am joined by Shawn Harris and Alix Kammeyer from Fidelity National Title to discuss this important real estate quandary.

I often meet with a seller only to find that they are not the person listed on the title. If this situation arises, the first important thing to know is how a property is vested.

Imagine the following scenario: A husband and wife named Robert and Susan are on the title as joint tenants on a property. Now Susan has passed away and Robert is attempting to list the property, but he has not done anything to indicate his wife’s passing on the title.

In this situation, Robert can still proceed with listing, but he will need to provide a valid copy of Susan’s death certificate and sign an affidavit of death of joint tenants.

But what about when a family owns a home in a trust? How does this impact a person’s ability to list?

To explain this, let’s return to the scenario we mentioned earlier. In this version of our example, Robert and Susan are still a married couple, Susan has passed away, and their property is owned in a trust. Before Robert can list, the title company will need to see the trust and verify that Susan was one of the trustees and that Robert is the only other trustee.

“A lot goes into listing a home, especially if ownership issues are at play.”

From there, the process will proceed in the same way as we previously described. Robert will still need to provide the two documents mentioned earlier, but, other than that, he would be able to proceed with listing.

Finally, how can ownership of a property be impacted as a result of a divorce? In the state of California, 50% of marriages do not work out. So, this question is sure to be on the minds of many as they prepare to list.

There are a couple of ways this scenario can unfold. Let’s use our imaginary couple, Robert and Susan, to explain once more. This time, imagine that Robert and Susan have been divorced for five or six years. Susan has quitclaimed her interest off because Robert was awarded the property, and she is now living in Europe. If Robert has not refinanced the home or had title insurance issued, he will need to acquire an affidavit of uninsured deed.

This can be very difficult to obtain, so the first step before this comes into play is to look at the marriage settlement agreement and verify that Robert was truly awarded the property. Once this is verified, another important point to check is that Susan didn’t sign the quitclaim under duress.

As is apparent, a lot goes into listing a home, especially if ownership issues are at play. It is critical to get in touch with a title company before proceeding with your sale to make sure everything goes smoothly.

If you are looking for more information and want to get in touch with Shawn or Alix, you can contact them with the following information:

Shawn Harrisshawn@mytitleandescrow.com(760) 271-8584

Alix Kammeyeralix@mytitleandescrow.com(619) 933-9621

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Do+You+Really+Know+Who+Owns+the+Property%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Do+You+Really+Know+Who+Owns+the+Property%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The issue of ownership is very important when it comes time to list a home. Today we will discuss a few key scenarios about listing after ownership-related complications arise.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The issue of ownership is very important when it comes time to list a home. Today we will discuss a few key scenarios about listing after ownership-related complications arise.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Here's How to Build a Granny Flat in San Diego</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/heres-how-to-build-a-granny-flat-in-san-diego.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-11 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Here%2527s+How+to+Build+a+Granny+Flat+in+San+Diego.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you thinking about building an ADU or granny flat on your property? Today I have Ian Scattergood with me to talk about the guidelines for San Diego.

 

Are you looking to build a granny flat or accessory unit on your property? Today we have Ian Scattergood, a permit pro, with us to discuss how to get a granny flat or accessory dwelling unit built (ADU) on your property in San Diego.

This has become a very popular topic in San Diego for many reasons. Some people want to rent out space for income on Airbnb or VRBO, while others simply want their guests to have a place to stay during their visits.

An accessory dwelling unit (ADU) is a second rentable unit on a single-family developed lot. There are some basic rules in San Diego for those people who want to build an ADU. The state requires a minimum size of 150 square feet and a maximum of 1,200 square feet. It must also have bathing facilities and cooking facilities, which can be a ¾ bath and a kitchenette.

Each jurisdiction can have either more restrictive or less restrictive guidelines than the state.

“Each jurisdiction can have either more restrictive or less restrictive guidelines than what the state has.”

To get started, you can call Ian’s office and provide the address at which you are considering building the ADU. He will Google the location to decide if it is a prime candidate to move forward and then contact you about what he thinks. Based on your jurisdiction, he can provide the guidelines and can help you decide if you want to consider building.

Some people in San Diego may want to convert a current space, such as another garage or craft room, into a livable space. You can take an old garage, shed, or legally permitted granny flat and convert it into a unit as long as it abides by new fire &amp; life safety codes. A new law provides relaxed setbacks and off-street parking guidelines.

You can contact Ian for more information about if your property qualifies at (619) 579-0088.

If you want to know more about the real estate market here in San Diego, please don’t hesitate to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.

Ian ScattergoodPermit Pro Consultants(619) 579-0088ian@permitprosd.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Here%2527s+How+to+Build+a+Granny+Flat+in+San+Diego.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/Here%2527s+How+to+Build+a+Granny+Flat+in+San+Diego.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you thinking about building an ADU or Granny Flat on your property? Today I have Ian Scattergood with me to talk about the guidelines for San Diego.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you thinking about building an ADU or Granny Flat on your property? Today I have Ian Scattergood with me to talk about the guidelines for San Diego.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should Homebuyers Know About Looking Over the Title Report?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-homebuyers-know-about-looking-over-the-title-report.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-25 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/What+Should+Homebuyers+Know+About+Looking+Over+the+Title+Report%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking over the title report as a buyer is an important step in real estate process. Today I&rsquo;ve brought on two experts to explain why this is.

 

So, you’ve made an offer on a home, gotten accepted, and received a copy of the title report. Now what?

Today I’m joined by Shawn and Alex from Fidelity Title to talk about a common question: What do you do with a title report once you’re in escrow?

For buyers, looking at the preliminary title report will be very important. This title report will alert you to things such as easements and CC&amp;Rs. First of all, many of you may be wondering: “What’s a CC&amp;R, and why should I care?”

This is a great question. CC&amp;R stands for covenants, codes, and restrictions. Basically, CC&amp;Rs are standards that govern what you can and cannot do to a property. If you wanted to paint your home pink, for example, you would look to your home’s CC&amp;Rs to see if doing so would be allowed. CC&amp;Rs for condos might even dictate the size, weight, and number of pets you can have.

These standards sound similar to what you might find with an HOA, but many homes outside of any HOA still come with CC&amp;Rs.

“For buyers, looking at the preliminary title report will be very important.”

Special programs are another thing that can appear on title reports. Homes with solar panels present one common example of when these programs come into play. Solar panels can be leased or purchased. Leased solar panels may fall within the Purchase Power Program or the Hero Program.

With the Hero Program, the tax bill will show the amount owed on a yearly basis. When you examine this tax bill as a buyer, you want to ensure that this is listed as a line item on the exception. However, if you don’t see it on the tax bill, it doesn’t mean the program doesn’t exist. It all depends on when the seller got the program.

When you do business with my team and I, Shawn and Alex go through every single title report to make sure there’s nothing wrong. We’re truly lucky to have their help.

If you are looking for more information and want to get in touch with Shawn or Alix, you can contact them with the following information:

Shawn Harrisshawn@mytitleandescrow.com(760) 271-8584

Alix Kammeyeralix@mytitleandescrow.com(619) 933-9621

And as always, if you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/What+Should+Homebuyers+Know+About+Looking+Over+the+Title+Report%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Videos/What+Should+Homebuyers+Know+About+Looking+Over+the+Title+Report%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Looking over the title report as a buyer is an important step in real estate process. Today, I’ve brought on two experts to explain why this is.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Looking over the title report as a buyer is an important step in real estate process. Today, I’ve brought on two experts to explain why this is.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Escrow Security Is Evolving</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-escrow-security-is-evolving.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-16 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Security+and+Escrow.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we are joined by special guest Molly O’Dell of Oakwood Escrow, and we were so excited to have her join us. We talked about security, escrow, and what has changed in the last year.

Email hacking is happening in every other industry and around the world, so why wouldn’t it happen in real estate? There is so much money going back and forth and these hackers are getting smart. They are watching the MLS, keeping an eye on pending transactions, then they hack the system and try to steal the buyer’s money via bogus wiring instructions. We’ve heard many horror stories about this kind of thing happening lately.

If your escrow company isn’t savvy enough with their digital security, you could lose your money so easily as a buyer. Encrypted emails may be an extra step and a tad annoying, but it is really worth it. We have to encrypt our emails to make sure that our clients are safe.

“We’ve seen too many buyers get scammed.”

One other thing that Molly thinks is important is to stop emailing wiring instructions. It’s commonly known that this is how hackers have stolen a lot of money in the past few years. At Oakwood Escrow, Molly and her team do not send wiring instructions via email. They can send them over the phone, via fax, or text message. It’s a lot safer than doing it over email.

If you have any questions about the escrow process in the meantime, you can give Molly a call at (619) 889-5639 or send an email to modell@oakwoodescrow.com.

If you have any other real estate related questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Security+and+Escrow.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Security+and+Escrow.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Molly O’Dell joined us recently to talk about escrow security advances. Here’s what we learned.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Molly O’Dell joined us recently to talk about escrow security advances. Here’s what we learned.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering 3 Common Escrow Questions</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/answering-3-common-escrow-questions.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-05 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+3+Questions+About+Escrow.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a lot of moving parts to every real estate transaction, and many people aren’t sure what happens during closing and escrow. Today, special guest Molly O’Dell from Oakwood Escrow is here to answer the three top escrow questions we get from our clients. 

1. When is closing and what does that mean here in San Diego? 

The closing date is based off the contract that the Realtor gives to the escrow company. Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days, although Molly says that it can be shorter or longer. At closing, all of the documents are signed and approved by all parties in the transaction: the lender, the title company, the buyer, and the seller. 

“Closing usually takes 30 to 45 days.”

2. As a seller, when will the money from your home sale hit your bank account? 

At closing, everything is sent to the title company within 24 hours, or the next business day. Your funds will probably hit your bank account the day after that, so you will get your money about 24 to 48 hours after closing the hold or file. 

3. Why do you have to sign documents with your Realtor and then sign documents with the escrow company? 

Your escrow company is a neutral third party. Although you signed contracts with your real estate agent allowing the escrow company to be part of the transaction, you still have to sign new documents with the escrow company. According to Molly, you don’t want your agent to sign your escrow documents because the escrow company is supposed to be a completely neutral third party. 

An independent escrow company is very important to both buyers and sellers. An independent escrow company doesn’t have a hand in the buyer agent’s commission or the listing agent’s commission. There are some in-house escrow companies that are affiliated with real estate agents. If they are under the same roof and same name as a real estate agent, they will obviously have a preferred party in each transaction. Molly says that the value of an independent escrow company is that they are able to step back and help both sides equally. 

If you have any other questions for Molly, you can reach her at modell@oakwoodescrow.com or (619) 889-5639. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+3+Questions+About+Escrow.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+3+Questions+About+Escrow.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Molly O’Dell from Oakwood Escrow is here to answer the top three questions we get from our clients about closing and escrow.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Molly O’Dell from Oakwood Escrow is here to answer the top three questions we get from our clients about closing and escrow.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will the Rise in Loan Limits This Year Impact the Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-will-the-rise-in-loan-limits-this-year-impact-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-31 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Loan+Limits.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I have with me special guest Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage, the man of all things mortgage. He’ll be discussing the rise in loan limits this year and how that can help you win in the San Diego real estate market.

According to Todd, the situation incredible—this is the biggest rise in loan limits that we’ve seen in a couple years. Conforming loan limits are up to $453,100 for single-family residents in San Diego. On high balance loan limits, we went up to $679,650.

This is unbelievable because it means that when you’re looking at something in the $800,000 range and putting down 20%, you’ve got a great opportunity to get conforming interest rates. In the past, you’d have to go through the jumbo loan process.

It also pertains to multi-units. Todd sees a lot of clients who own triplexes and were limited on how much cash they could pull out of those properties who can now pull cash out at much higher numbers than they could last year. Now they’re able to use that to buy more properties or pay down their mortgage on their personal residences. They can take advantage of both sides of the equation.

On our end, with the mid-range, detached home prices in the mid-$700,000 price point in San Diego, being able to have this high loan balance lowers the amount that people are required to put down on a higher-priced home. People are able to get the home they want in the time they want at the rate that makes sense for them.

“This is the biggest rise in loan limits that we’ve seen in a couple years.”

Another cool aspect, according to Todd, is that these new limits also pertain to VA and FHA loans. It means that you have a 3.5%-down FHA program where you can basically buy a mid-range, detached home and get an incredible interest rate. With the VA loan, you can put 0% down. This could actually stimulate the marketrather than hurt it, as people are concerned about with the recent tax reform. It will help both first-time and experienced homebuyers.

We are really excited to be able to help families in 2018. If he can be of help to you, Todd can be reached at (858) 775-8958 or tpianin@rpm-mtg.com.

Todd Pianin, Regional Manager NMLS# 304014

LendUS, LLC dba RPM Mortgage NMLS #1938 - Licensed by the Department of Business Oversight under the CA Residential Mortgage Lending Act. Equal Housing Opportunity.

If you have any questions or need any tips and tricks on how to win in the San Diego real estate market, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help you out this year.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Loan+Limits.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Loan+Limits.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Loan limits in 2018 are on the rise. Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage will discuss the impacts this will have on the market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Loan limits in 2018 are on the rise. Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage will discuss the impacts this will have on the market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Important Mortgage Information for Millennial Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/important-mortgage-information-for-millennial-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-18 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Millennials+in+the+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m happy to be joined by a special guest, Todd Pianin of RPM Mortgage, to have a discussion about millennial homebuyers in the San Diego market. Todd has some awesome lending tips that will help any millennial who is looking to buy their first home become competitive in the market.

Many millennials grew up during the 2007 credit crisis. Therefore, a lot of them only deal with cash and don’t have credit cards. If you’re a millennial that doesn’t have a credit card but wants to buy a house, you should know that you’ll need to have at least three different cards in order to purchase one. It’s important that you start building your credit now, especially if homeownership is in your future plans.

One other big problem we’ve run into with millennials is a lack of rental history. If you’re in a situation where you’re living with a friend and renting a room from them, you should ask to get added to the lease. If you’ve been out of college for a few years and don’t have any rental history, it’s pretty hard to get qualified for a mortgage.

“Start building your credit now.”

If you do have all of your ducks in a row, it gives you a huge advantage in the marketplace. Inventory is so tight now in San Diego and there’s talk of even less inventory in the future. By having good credit and a solid rental history, Todd and his team can issue you an advanced approval in order to get your fully approved (subject to appraisal, escrow, and title). This will allow you to close on a home in just 14 days, which is much quicker than the average buyer.

If you’re ready to start the pre-approval process or you just have any questions about credit or mortgages in general, give Todd a call at (858) 775-8958 or send an email over to Tpianin@rpm-mtg.com. If you have any other questions for us about the San Diego real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out anytime. We look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Millennials+in+the+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Millennials+in+the+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you a millennial homebuyer or thinking about becoming one soon? If so, we have some great tips to share today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you a millennial homebuyer or thinking about becoming one soon? If so, we have some great tips to share today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Prevent a Home Sale From Falling Apart</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-prevent-a-home-sale-from-falling-apart.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-02 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Reasons+Deals+Fall+Apart.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you ever found yourself in the process of buying or selling a home only for something to go wrong?

Whether this has ever happened to you or not, I would like to share some tips today on how to prevent a real estate transaction from falling apart. During any transaction, there are three main hurdles. Let’s take a look at what they are and how to overcome them:


  The inspection. Sometimes, this is the point where a buyer may find something they dislike about the home and simply walk away. The issue they find may not even be all that significant. Still, it can be confusing to a seller to have this happen, especially if their home was receiving multiple offers. For this reason, I recommend that sellers get rid of as many of these small issues as they can ahead of time. Anything you can fix for under $100 could make a big difference. During a real estate transaction, preparation such as this is key.
  Appraisals. Problems related to appraisals typically come up due to lack of preparation. To help combat that, my team and I like to accompany our client in meeting the appraiser on the property when entering escrow. The appraiser probably doesn’t know the neighborhood of the home as well as our client or we might. This additional step can really demonstrate the value of the property so that the home is more likely to appraise.
  The loan. Too many buyers out there aren’t truly pre-approved. When we have a buyer open escrow with us on our listings, we cross-qualify them with our lender just to be sure. This prevents people from spending a lot of money on a transaction only to realize they aren’t qualified to buy a home.


“During a real estate transaction, preparation is key.”

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Reasons+Deals+Fall+Apart.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Reasons+Deals+Fall+Apart.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a number of ways that a real estate transaction can fall apart. Today, I’d like to share the three most common hurdles people face, as well as how to overcome them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a number of ways that a real estate transaction can fall apart. Today, I’d like to share the three most common hurdles people face, as well as how to overcome them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It Possible to Find the Right Home During Our Current Inventory Crisis?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-it-possible-to-find-the-right-home-during-our-current-inventory-crisis.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-19 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Inventory+Crisis.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you struggling to find a home here in San Diego County? 

San Diego is in an inventory crisis right now. There are simply more buyers than there are available homes. So when a property does get listed, it receives a lot of attention. 

Today, I’ve got three tips and tricks for helping you win out in our local real estate market:

1. Work with an active agent or team. Who you work with really does matter. You need to be working with a busy agent or team who is in touch with the current market. My team and I are always dedicated to searching out and following up on deals. When you work with us, we can offer you valuable inside knowledge on how to secure a property. 

2. Find an agent that is constantly working to find new properties. Professionals who keep a constant eye on the market are going to help you immensely when it comes to finding the right home. Your chances will be even better if an agent can bring you a property that few people know about yet. The less competition a home sees, the better your chances are. 

3. Make sure you find out about off-market properties. Don’t forget to check out properties that were listed a few years ago and have been recently relisted. These homes could present you with some unique opportunities.

“The less competition a listing sees, the better your chances are.”

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Inventory+Crisis.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Inventory+Crisis.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With San Diego in an inventory crisis, many buyers are struggling to find homes. Today, I’ve got some tips that can help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With San Diego in an inventory crisis, many buyers are struggling to find homes. Today, I’ve got some tips that can help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons Why the Holiday Season Is a Great Time to Sell Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-why-the-holiday-season-is-a-great-time-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-05 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Listing+During+the+Holidays.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are five reasons why the holiday season is a great time to sell your home. 

1. People who look for homes during this time are serious buyers. They’re looking to close before the end of the year or the early part of January. If there are fewer homes on the market and you’re looking at the competition, you have to make a decision. 

2. The supply of homes decreases. Fewer and fewer homes come on the market toward the end of the year because people who tested the market earlier in the year usually decide to pull their homes off the MLS and wait until next year. That leaves only serious sellers looking to make a deal and move before the end of the year. 

3. People may need to move for tax and timing reasons. A lot of folks may be 1031-ing out of a particular property or need to close before the end of the year for tax reasons. These people are likely to make a decision, close fast, and make it easy for you as a seller to move or potentially rent back until the beginning of next year so it doesn’t interrupt your holiday schedule. 

4. By selling your home now, you can become a non-contingent buyer in the spring. 

5. Your home shows better during the holidays. You’ll likely have friends and family visiting you sometime, so you’ll probably do a little extra cleaning and decorating anyway to make sure your home is spic and span. 

“Buyers are far more serious this time of year.”

If you have any more questions about selling your home in the fall or you’re curious about our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to get together and chat with you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Listing+During+the+Holidays.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Listing+During+the+Holidays.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re wondering whether the holiday season is a good time to sell your home, I have five reasons that will help you decide.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re wondering whether the holiday season is a good time to sell your home, I have five reasons that will help you decide.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Owning a Second Home in San Diego</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/owning-a-second-home-in-san-diego.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Second+Homes+in+San+Diego.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve put together some tips and tricks regarding buying a second home in San Diego, specifically some tax considerations you should talk over with your CPA if you’re thinking about buying a second home in the San Diego area.


  Mortgage interest deduction: Here in San Diego, you can write off the mortgage interest on your property for up to a million dollars. That can get you a great place near the beach, downtown, up in Carlsbad, or a ranch property somewhere in San Diego.
  Writing off your property taxes: You can write off all your property taxes without a limit. There is a caveat, however. If your annual income puts you in a tax bracket over $311,000, there are limits to how much you can write off, so make sure you talk with your CPA about how much of a write off you are allowed.
  Renting out your second property: Did you know you can rent out your San Diego property for up to 14 days and not pay any taxes on that income? That means your second property can become a source of tax-free income over holiday weekends like the Fourth of July, or over winter break when a lot the snowbirds are coming down to San Diego to catch some sunshine. It is possible to rent out your second property and have two or three months worth of your annual mortgage covered by the tax-free income from that 14 days of rental. It is important to remember that renting beyond 14 days a year makes that income taxable and can change the status of your second property to a rental property.
  You can shift your primary residence: When it comes time to sell, you may consider making your second home in San Diego your primary residence. In doing so, a married couple can avoid paying up to $500,000 in capital-gains taxes.


“It is possible to rent out your second property and have two to three months worth of your annual mortgage covered by the tax-free income from that 14 days of rental.”

If you’re considering making that purchase of a second home here in San Diego, these are some subjects that could save you a lot of money and that you should definitely talk to a CPA about. If you’d like to talk to me or have any questions, feel free to contact me at (858) 229-6063 or online at sean@mysddreamhome.com. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Second+Homes+in+San+Diego.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Second+Homes+in+San+Diego.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering a second home in the San Diego area, there are four interesting facts regarding taxes that can help you save a lot of money.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering a second home in the San Diego area, there are four interesting facts regarding taxes that can help you save a lot of money.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Overlook These Critical Property Features</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-overlook-these-critical-property-features.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Things+Not+To+Overlook.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There’s a lot to think about whenever you’re taking steps to purchase your next home. Of course, one of the first things to do is to sync up with a great real estate agent who’s really got your back.

Even so, there are a couple of things you shouldn’t overlook in your transaction. Even with the help of an agent, you want to pay close attention to certain aspects, yourself.

First, pay attention to the neighborhood. Typically speaking, you’ll visit properties with your real estate agent around a pretty consistent time of day. My team and I personally recommend revisiting any property you’re interested in at different times, to get a true feel for the community and know exactly what you’re getting.

Next, ask yourself what your commute will be like. Your lifestyle should be a key consideration in your decision on whether to buy a certain home.Whether you want to be close to work, to school, to family, or to a lot of restaurants, it’s important to know how far you’re going to need to travel.

Also, be sure to look into the rules of the community. A lot of communities in our area have homeowners associations or CC&amp;Rs (Covenants, Conditions, and Restrictions) that may impact things like the colors you can paint your home, what you can park in front of your house, and what kinds of pets are allowed.

“Make sure a property matches your long-term goals.”

Another thing people sometimes forget is to critically consider the bedroom-to-bathroom ratio. Think realistically about how much space you and your family are going to need.Even something that may work for you now may not work in the future if you plan on growing your family. Before deciding on a home, really think about what makes sense for you.

You should also make sure to change your HVAC systems. A lot of property in San Diego has septic systems, solar systems, wells, and other features. Look into what maintenance is going to cost you.

Another question to ask yourself is if you’re okay with features that can’t be changed. Things like location, lot size, and the floor plan are all features you’re going to have to live with for however long you stay.Make sure you’re happy with them.

Also think about your resale value. You need to have a clear understanding of what it costs to own the home, what the home’s potential value is, and what rents are going for in the neighborhood in case you ever decide to rent the property out.

Finally, decide if a given property will realistically be sufficient for you and your family’s growth in a long-term sense. Depending on how long you want to stay on a property, you really need to think about this factor. My team and I often see people try to squeeze into a home that is too small, simply because it fits their budget.Don’t make this same mistake. Make sure a property matches your long-term goals.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Things+Not+To+Overlook.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Things+Not+To+Overlook.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re searching the market for your next home, there are a few critical aspects you should never overlook in the process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re searching the market for your next home, there are a few critical aspects you should never overlook in the process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>9 Home Repairs You Can’t Afford to Ignore</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/9-home-repairs-you-cant-afford-to-ignore.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-28 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+9+Home+Repairs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m back with some more tips and tricks to help you win in the San Diego real estate market. Whether you’re thinking of selling your home soon or just looking to increase its value, there are a number of home repairs that you definitely should not put off when they are needed. Here are nine of them to keep an eye on:

1. Caulking around areas where there may be exposed water. This includes bathrooms, kitchens, windows, and anywhere else where water can penetrate. We had a home on the market that didn’t pay attention to this and it ended up costing the owners $10,000 to fix the kitchen when it flooded. It’s much easier to buy a $10 caulking gun at the hardware store.

2. Cleaning your dryer vent. So many people forget to do this. You should have it cleaned at least once a year to prevent a fire hazard.

3. Roof repairs. With sun and water constantly hitting our roofs in San Diego, they can get eaten up pretty quickly. Any time you find a roof leak or imperfection, call a roofer. It’s better to spend a few hundred now than a few thousand later.

4. Chimney sweep. For a few hundred bucks, there are plenty of companies out there that will come out and do a full sweep of all your chimneys to further reduce fire hazards.

5. Change your HVAC filters. When people don’t change their filters for months or even years, they get clogged and bog down the system. That can cause it to burn out. Get these filters changed often.

6. Pest problems. Whether it’s termites, rodents, or other pests, you want to handle any pest problems very early on. It can get very expensive if you don’t.

7. Fix any plumbing leaks as soon as you find them. This is one of the more costly repairs that we see. A simple leaky pipe can cause major damage if not handled properly.

8. Peeling paint. If you see any chipped, cracked, or peeling paint, throw a fresh coat on top. 

9. Drainage problems. We see this a lot in homes with plants or sprinklers near the house. The stucco next to the house tends to get eaten away quite quickly. If that’s the case for you, it’s time to change to a drip system to make your home ready for the next time we get a big winter rain.

“Pests need to be dealt with immediately.”

These are just a few things that you should stay on top of as a homeowner, whether you’re thinking of selling soon or not. If you are and you need any assistance from us, we’d be happy to help. Just give us a call or send us an email today.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+9+Home+Repairs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+9+Home+Repairs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are certain home repairs you shouldn’t ignore. If you do, it will end up being a much more expensive fix down the line.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are certain home repairs you shouldn’t ignore. If you do, it will end up being a much more expensive fix down the line.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Make Your Appliances Last Longer and Perform Better With These 9 Tricks</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/make-your-appliances-last-longer-and-perform-better-with-these-9-tricks.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-14 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Extend+the+Life+of+Appliances.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Each year, we sell many homes to many great clients, and 90 days to six months later, we hear about something breaking in their house—usually a major appliance.

To avoid this situation, here are 9 tips and tricks you can use to extend the life of your home’s appliances and improve their performance.


  Keep your refrigerator and freezer clean. Change the filters, make sure calcium doesn’t build up inside the tubing, and empty the ice trays.
  Defrost your freezer. So many of us have items that have been in our freezer for many months, so throw that stuff out and remove the frost so your freezer isn’t working so hard to produce ice.
  Scrub the bottom of your oven. When you have an oven, crumbs and other food particles tend to accumulate at the bottom. Don’t set tin foil down to remedy this—that’s bad for your oven. Instead, use a little elbow grease and scrub that part of your oven down.
  Replace any filters in your AC unit or any other appliance that has filters. As filters get clogged, their machines have to work harder to pass air and energy through them, which can lead to them breaking down sooner. Whether it’s an HVAC unit or a water filtration system, not replacing their filters can cost you thousands of dollars.
  Use detergent instead of soap in your dishwasher. Use only the types of goods that are prescribed by your appliance for that appliance.
  Scrape your dishes before putting them in your dishwasher. Don’t just throw all of them in there without scraping off the gunk and grime first.
  Don’t overload your washer or dryer. They each have a capacity, so if you’re washing and drying a lot of clothes on a regular basis, buy a new washer and dryer. If you overload them, they have to work a lot harder, and they can be very expensive to fix and replace.
  To improve your dryer’s circulation, make sure its exhaust system is cleaned once a year. People usually just pull the lint tray out and clean that, but a lot of lint can also get stuck in the tubing that leads to the exterior of the house, and many people invest in a boost fan to push that lint out.
  Don’t pour stain remover into the washer or store any bottles like that on top of it. These bottles can get hot and melt while the washer is in use and spill all over the machine.


“Not replacing your filters can cost you thousands of dollars.”

If you have any questions about these tips and tricks or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in the San Diego area, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Extend+the+Life+of+Appliances.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Extend+the+Life+of+Appliances.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are 9 simple tricks you can do to extend the life of your home’s appliances and improve their performance.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are 9 simple tricks you can do to extend the life of your home’s appliances and improve their performance.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It a Wise Move to Invest in an Airbnb Property?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-it-a-wise-move-to-invest-in-an-airbnb-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-31 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Air+BnB.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, Airbnb came out with a study saying they contribute $420 million dollars to the local economy here in San Diego each year. That’s a big number, and we have a lot of clients asking us whether they should consider buying an Airbnb property or converting a property they already own into one. 

If you’re asking yourself the same thing, the answer depends on a few different factors.

For example, the city of Del Mar recently changed the restrictions on how you can rent out your property—they limited the rental period to fewer than 30 days and lessened the number of times you can rent out your property to four times per year. 

For decades, coastal cities have thrived off residents renting out their homes during the summer while they vacationed or traveled elsewhere. This means people visiting these coastal cities who couldn’t necessarily afford a hotel or were looking to bring their whole family along are getting squeezed out of the local market.

So, is it still worthwhile to buy an Airbnb property?

Our investor clients are still making lots of money off these properties, they’re super happy with them, and they’re calling us daily looking for more properties to use for this purpose. 

“Our investor clients are still making lots of money off Airbnb properties.”

To find a good Airbnb property, the first thing you want to examine is whether there is demand for hotel stays in your area. If your community doesn’t have a lot of hotel options and many people travel to it, look into those demographics. 

Next, consider your budget and whether it’s even worth buying an Airbnb property in your area. Also, weigh your time commitment. The biggest management issue we’ve seen with clients is deciding whether they should do it themselves or hire a management company. 

When advising our clients on these matters, we break it down to the very basics of buying a rental property—does the rent in the area cover the cost of owning that property and does it makes sense?

There are a lot of reasons people buy property for Airbnb or VRBO purposes, but when we sell a client a property, we figure out if the property makes sense from an investment perspective. Once we align with our client’s goals for that perspective, then we talk about whether they should consider renting it out as an Airbnb property. 

If you’re looking for a property you’d like to rent out as an Airbnb or you already own a property you want to transfer into an Airbnb property, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Air+BnB.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Air+BnB.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering buying an Airbnb property, you must weigh a few different factors before making a decision.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering buying an Airbnb property, you must weigh a few different factors before making a decision.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Solar Panels Help Homes Sell for More Money?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-solar-panels-help-homes-sell-for-more-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-18 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Solar+Panels.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What should you know about solar panels before buying them yourself? We’ve got some tips to share with you today that may help you make your decision.

We aren’t experts in solar energy, but we are experts in real estate values and what solar energy systems do to them. What we’ve noticed is that homes that are sold with solar systems tend to sell for more money. This is only for solar systems that have been purchased, however.

Solar energy systems that are leased have the opposite effect. Homes can sell for as much as $100,000 less with leased solar systems than if they didn’t have a system at all. This is because most buyers are hesitant to pick up the extra costs. Although a leased solar system is cheaper in the short term, a purchased solar system has a much higher resale value. 

“Buyers are always hesitant to pick up extra fees.”

Buyers are hesitant to pick up any extra fees, let alone the fees for a system they probably don’t know too much about. There’s just not as much education for people who are looking to lease solar panels today in the middle of a real estate transaction.

If you are a homeowner already and looking at adding a solar energy system, think about how long you will be in the home. If you’re going to be there longer than a few years, purchasing a system is your best investment.

We wanted to share those quick tips with you just in case you’ve been considering getting a solar energy system. If you have any other questions about these systems or about anything else related to real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Solar+Panels.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Solar+Panels.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is solar energy a wise investment? It depends on where you’re at.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is solar energy a wise investment? It depends on where you’re at.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Win the Home You Want as a Contingent Buyer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-the-home-you-want-as-a-contingent-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-17 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Contingent+Buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is a contingent buyer? This is someone who is looking to buy their next home while still having to sell their current home. In today’s marketplace, this is one of the hottest topics that we’re running into. We have a couple of tips on how to plan your next move.

1. Be very clear on your goals. What are you looking to achieve? In our first consultation, we will sit down with you and get all the information about exactly what you’re looking for so we can find the home that fits your needs.

2. Prep your home before listing. We want to make sure that your home is prepped and ready to go before you list it. That means you’re going to want to declutter and stage your home before we list so that when you move, it’s a steady transition from the old home to the new one.

You also need to get out there and look at some homes. What we do with each one of our clients is look at homes prior to putting their home on the market. You need to see what’s out there and see what’s going to fit for your family and their needs.

“Get out there and look at some homes to see what’s available out there for you and your family.”

3. Have the same agent represent you on both properties. Not only will it save you some money in the long run, but because you’re dealing with two transactions, having the same agent to take you through the entire process will remove some of the hassle. That way you have the same agent who understands your needs and will be able to act in accordance with those needs.

4. Take a look at time frames. Time frames are important because when you accept an offer on your house or get an offer accepted on your next house, you want to make sure that you don’t feel rushed during the moving process.

These are just a couple of tips to help our clients win in the contingent market today. If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, please give us a call. We look forward to working with you!

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Contingent+Buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Contingent+Buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In today’s contingent market, there are a couple things that we do to make sure that our clients win the home of their dreams.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In today’s contingent market, there are a couple things that we do to make sure that our clients win the home of their dreams.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Has the Real Estate Market Peaked Yet?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/has-the-real-estate-market-peaked-yet.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-19 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Has+the+Market+Peaked.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are we at the peak of the real estate market? The short answer is no, not yet. 
 
The last time the market peaked, interest rates were in the low 6% range. Lenders would give loans to just about anybody, so we had people who weren’t really qualified to get a loan end up with 100% financing or more on a property they may not have even been living in—they might have been flipping the property. 
 
This caused mass chaos in the marketplace, and affordability dropped all the way down to 9%.  
 
Right now, interest rates are still in the low 4% range. Lending conditions haven’t eased up in the last five to seven years, so the homebuyers who have been approved are strong borrowers with great down payments. The market also continues to increase, and affordability is around 26%. 
 
Historically speaking, when a market has a shift or correction, affordability is around the mid to high teens. 

“Our market still has room to grow, but we’re not sure by how much.”
So, what does this mean to you? 
 
Ultimately, our market still has quite a bit of room to grow, and we’re not sure how much room there is. 
 
Home sellers can cash out on their equity and move into the dream home they’ve always wanted because they finally have the down payment. Homebuyers are locking in low interest rates for the next 15 to 30 years and moving into great communities with long-term growth. Overall, now is still a great time to be in the market. 
 
If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Has+the+Market+Peaked.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Has+the+Market+Peaked.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Has the real estate market peaked yet? How can we tell?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Has the real estate market peaked yet? How can we tell?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Win the Home You Want in Our San Diego Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-the-home-you-want-in-our-san-diego-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+How's+the+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you looking to win the home you want in our current market? Here are a few statistics you can use that will help you do so. 
 
The first stat, which is a leading indicator of the real estate market, is the number of new homes coming on the market. At the moment, the number of new homes coming on the market is down 28% compared to this time last year. This means you have almost 30% fewer options than you did last year. 
 
The next stat we look at is homes going into escrow, or however many homes coming on the market that are actually selling right now. This number is almost unchanged from this time last year. Last year, there were 83 homes going into escrow; this year, there are 83 as well. This means if you’re out looking for homes, you will face a lot of competition. 
 
The last stat we’ll examine is home prices and how they stack up this year compared to last year. On average, homes prices are up 6.4% from this time last year. 

“Use these numbers to present your best possible offer.”
 
These numbers mean we’re in a very strong seller’s market. Homes are selling for all-time-high prices—even higher than the homes sold between 2004 and 2006. Any buyers out there looking for homes can expect to face stiff competition from other buyers. We’re seeing many make multiple offers on different homes before finding the one they want. 
 
As a buyer, you must be mindful of this information and do your research on the areas that are most important to you. Use these tactics to present the best possible offer and make sure you have a good agent writing that offer. That’s the best way to find the home you want in our market. 
 
If you have any more questions about our market or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+How's+the+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+How's+the+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are some important numbers from our current market that buyers should be mindful of when they’re out looking for homes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are some important numbers from our current market that buyers should be mindful of when they’re out looking for homes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Much Down Payment Do I Need to Buy a House?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-much-down-payment-do-i-need-to-buy-a-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-11 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+You+have+many+different+home+loan+options.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When buying a home, most people will need to get a loan. However, how much of a down payment will you need to put down to get certain loans?

You’ve got many different options. The first is a VA loan, which is a loan for active and former military servicemen and women. This loan gives back to those who defend our freedom by offering them a 0% down loan on amounts over $600,000.

The next product is the FHA loan. This loan is backed by the government and allows the buyer to purchase a home with just 3.5% down here in San Diego. This loan opens a lot of doors to traditional first-time homebuyers. You can get a great rate, get into the home you want, and start building equity.

“FHA loans are backed by the government.”

Finally, you have some conventional hybrid programs. One example is the 80-10-10, which lets you buy a more expensive home by combining an 80% conventional loan with another 10% loan.

To learn more about how you can buy a home today without investing much money up front, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+You+have+many+different+home+loan+options.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+You+have+many+different+home+loan+options.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You don’t need 20% down payment to buy a home. In fact, you might not even need a dime.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You don’t need 20% down payment to buy a home. In fact, you might not even need a dime.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should I Continue to Rent in San Diego?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-i-continue-to-rent-in-san-diego.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-27 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Renting+vs.+Buying.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I get asked by a lot of young professionals about the benefits of home buying. They want to know if they should continue renting or just suck it up and buy a home.

My initial response to them is that it depends. We’ve got to take a look at your goals, your income, and your debt, and everything else that goes along with buying a home.

Generally, the average rental rate for a 2-bedroom, 2-bathroom apartment is over $2,100 in San Diego. That’s a lot to be shelling out in rent.

Right now, with that same $2,100 going toward a mortgage payment, you could get a 2-bedroom, 2-bathroom condo here in the city in the mid $400,000 price range and still keep the same monthly cost.

“Buying isn’t for everybody.”

Another benefit of buying a home is that you can capture back your interest rate deduction when you file your taxes each year.You can’t do that with rent.

Buying isn’t for everybody, but we can walk you through the options to make sure you make a decision that best fits your lifestyle and your needs here in San Diego.

If you have any questions for me or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Renting+vs.+Buying.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Renting+vs.+Buying.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying a home isn’t more expensive than renting. In fact, it’s a little cheaper in our market to buy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying a home isn’t more expensive than renting. In fact, it’s a little cheaper in our market to buy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Our Big Move Impacts You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-our-big-move-impacts-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Move+to+KW.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve got some exciting news—we moved!

We’ve aligned our business with Keller Williams Realty here in the San Diego market. The whole team is coming with us and we’re very excited to take our service—and your experience—the next level.

Our new office is exciting and full of new energy. But what does it mean to you as a customer?

Quite a bit, actually. With our new partnership with Keller Williams, we’re able to bring you more tools and better service, which will let us take your buying and selling experience to the next level. 

“We’re able to bring you more tools and better service, which will let us take your buying and selling experience to the next level.”

Since we’re part of one of the biggest offices here in San Diego, we’re able to bring you deals that aren’t even on the market yet and expose your listing to all the top agents in San Diego County.

If you have any questions about what this move means to you or how we can better help you buy or sell a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Move+to+KW.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Move+to+KW.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We've got an exciting announcement to make that's all good news for you as a customer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We've got an exciting announcement to make that's all good news for you as a customer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Downsize Your Home Without Giving Up Your Lifestyle</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-to-downsize-your-home-without-giving-up-your-lifestyle.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Downsizing+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Downsizing has been a popular topic of discussion for us lately, so today I want to provide you three quick tips on how to get the process started if you’re thinking about downsizing.

First, start with a plan.

Write down what you want to keep, what you want to donate, and what doesn’t need to go with you. We can help you create that list and then organize, box up, and move all your possessions.

Next, look for that next house now. You need to know where you’re going before you put your home on the market so you have a good, realistic idea of what house you can get next. A good Realtor can help you clarify and list your living preferences and then show you a couple of homes that match up with them so you can get a taste of what your new lifestyle would be in your new neighborhood.

Lastly, start prepping your home for sale.

“Have a plan in place and know where you want to move next.”

We have many instructional videos on this topic for your perusal, and we can also meet with you in person to help you implement an action plan. With the biggest move of your life being a downsizing move, you want to make sure you’re prepared and ready to take those next steps as efficiently and effectively as possible so you can enjoy the next phase of your life.

If you’d like more downsizing tips or have any other real estate questions, feel free to give us a call or shoot us an email. We would love to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Downsizing+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Downsizing+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Downsizing can be a daunting task, but I have three tips to share that can make the process easier and more efficient for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Downsizing can be a daunting task, but I have three tips to share that can make the process easier and more efficient for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Now the Right Time to Sell Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-now-the-right-time-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-07 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Should+I+Sell.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I get asked all the time by people if they should sell their home now or wait. People want to know when the right time to sell is, and it’s an important question to ask. Before we list a home on the market we take the time to ask sellers a few different questions to figure out what their goals are and whether it does make sense for them to sell now or wait until a later time.


  Why are you moving? Are you upgrading or downsizing? Moving closer inland or more toward the coast? It’s the first thing we ask.


2. Do I have enough equity to sell? We constantly do evaluations for our clients to be able to give them the best information possible. Like a financial advisor would give you updates on how your investments are doing, we will give you updates on how your home’s equity is doing so you always know what’s going on.

3. Do interest rates have any effect on me selling? They truly do. Rates went up a bit immediately after the election and we saw a recent announcement that says they are going to go up even more. Contact us and we can help you get to the next step of the process.

4. What type of market is this? It really depends on where your home is. We break down exactly where you stand based on your home’s location.

“People want to know when the right time to sell is.”

If you have any further questions or want any other tips about getting a specific plan of action together, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Should+I+Sell.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Should+I+Sell.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot of people have been asking us about the right time to sell. The truth is, any time can be a good time if you have the right motivation.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot of people have been asking us about the right time to sell. The truth is, any time can be a good time if you have the right motivation.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Prepare for the Spring San Diego Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-prepare-for-the-spring-san-diego-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-20 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Spring+Sale+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As you might already know, spring starts quite a bit earlier in San Diego compared to other parts of the country. If you plan to sell your home this spring, these four steps will help you get the most out of your sale.


  Figure out how much your home is worth by calling a professional real estate agent who sells homes in your area, and maybe even get a second opinion. You want to know exactly what your home’s fair market value is and an approximate best time to sell it. An agent should also ask you questions about where you’re moving to and when you want to move.
  Consider what you have to do to get the home ready for sale. This could be as simple as decluttering your living room or putting some wood chips in the front yard, or all the way up to a light remodel. An agent will help you assess what the best move is to maximize your value.
  Find the right time to put your home on the market. Two things come into play here. Since we have nice weather here, we always recommend listing right after the Super Bowl when the maximum amount of buyers come out of the woodwork. The second thing we look at is how many other homes are on the market in your neighborhood. Sometimes, timing your sale for right after a few homes close could be the difference in you getting an extra $5,000, $10,000, or even $15,000. We can help you measure that and assess the market to be ready to go.
  Figure out when and how to show the home. This depends on whether you have kids and pets, your home’s location, and the demographic of the buyers for your neighborhood. We always say that the easier it is to show a home, the easier it is to sell for top dollar in a faster amount of time. We can coach you on how to achieve this, too.


“Preparing could be as easy as some fresh mulch in the front yard.”

If there’s anything my team and I can do to help you, just give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to helping you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Spring+Sale+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate+Spring+Sale+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you plan to sell your house this spring, I have four tips that will help you get ready to sell quickly for the most money possible.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you plan to sell your house this spring, I have four tips that will help you get ready to sell quickly for the most money possible.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Win in a Multiple Offer Situation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-23 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++How+to+stand+out+in+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You’ve gone through the work of finding your dream home, and you’ve submitted an offer. Unfortunately, your offer isn’t the only one on the table. How can you make sure your offer gets accepted in a multiple offer situation? Use these three tips to ensure you end up with your dream home.


  Do not underestimate the importance of your agent. You need to make sure your agent is in direct contact with the listing agent and knows what’s happening, what offers are coming in, and what price points the sellers are looking at. The more communication your agent has with the listing agent, the higher the probability that you’re going to get your offer accepted. The listing agent wants to know that you are easy to communicate with if they were to go into escrow with you and your agent.
  Make sure you send something personal. Something like a letter or a short video is going to make you look like a more appealing buyer, rather than just giving them a number, an offer, and an email. Send something that lets the seller know you’re human, and really let them know your story. They might end up having something in common with you, which could sway them in your direction.
  Find out why they’re moving, and where they’re moving to. Get as much information as you possibly can about the sellers. They might have hot buttons, and the more you know, the more prepared you can be to make a personal plea to go with your offer.


“Make sure you end up with your dream home”

If you have any further questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++How+to+stand+out+in+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++How+to+stand+out+in+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re looking to buy a home, you need to be prepared in case of a multiple offer situation. Use these three tips to make sure both you and your offer stand out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re looking to buy a home, you need to be prepared in case of a multiple offer situation. Use these three tips to make sure both you and your offer stand out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Keys to Getting Your Home Sold</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-keys-to-getting-your-home-sold.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-30 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++3+Tips+for+Home+Prepping.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of sellers have been asking us what they should do when preparing their homes for sale, so we’ve got a few tips to share with you. Here are three things you should absolutely do before putting your home on the market:


  Declutter. We all have personal items in our home. If you remove them before you sell, it makes things less cluttered and simpler for the buyers, allowing them to focus on the space itself. If you have any extra furniture that is out of place, consider storing it in your garage or a storage unit.
  Depersonalization. Take the magnets off the fridge and the family photos off the wall. We want your home to feel as neutral as possible for buyers.
  Make noticeable repairs. If something obviously needs to be fixed, get it taken care of whether it’s a bad doorbell, a front door, or a light bulb. These are simple things that you or a handyman can take care of before listing your home for sale.


“Magnets and family photos don’t help sell homes.”

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++3+Tips+for+Home+Prepping.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++3+Tips+for+Home+Prepping.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Before putting your home on the market, you should prepare it in a few specific ways. Decluttering and depersonalizing will go a long way in highlighting your home’s features.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Before putting your home on the market, you should prepare it in a few specific ways. Decluttering and depersonalizing will go a long way in highlighting your home’s features.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Renovations Should Home Sellers Avoid?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-renovations-should-home-sellers-avoid.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-02 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Top+5+Renovations+for+Home+Sellers+to+Avoid.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I get asked all the time what sellers should do to get their homes ready for the market. While there are many things that you should do, today, I want to share a few home renovations you should definitely avoid. 

First of all, wallpaper is out. Don’t add wallpaper to your home unless you’re in a very selective, custom home or we’ve had some designers come in. If that’s not the case, throwing up some Home Depot wallpaper is not the way to go. 

Secondly, keep the light fixtures simple. People don’t find a lot of value in extremely lavish light fixtures, especially in the middle price points. Instead of getting a lavish light fixture, stick with something clean and simple. 

The next thing to pay attention to is flooring. In high traffic areas, it’s common for older homes to have carpet in the hallway, living room, or dining room. Buyers do not want you to replace that flooring with more carpet. Instead, consider laminate flooring, inexpensive tile, or hardwood floors. There are a lot of entry level hardwoods that compete with carpet pricing that you could install in a day or two and will look amazing. 

Although you should paint your home, you should avoid bold colors. Stick to neutral paint colors instead. Bold reds, purples, and blues are a little too dark and a little too specific to most people’s tastes. Buyers want something a little more neutral and calming. 

“Stick to neutral, calming paint colors.”

Finally, consider skipping the swimming pool. Today, there is a big debate about water conservation here in California and whether or not it’s smart to put in a pool. How do you pay for it? Is it on solar? As a result, a lot of buyers are more hesitant about having a private pool. In fact, most would be happy with a community pool, which a lot of neighborhoods already have. 

Avoid these home renovations and you will have a successful home sale. If you have any other questions about preparing your home for the market or about real estate in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Top+5+Renovations+for+Home+Sellers+to+Avoid.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Top+5+Renovations+for+Home+Sellers+to+Avoid.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Although there are many things you should do to prepare your home for the market, there are also five home renovations you should avoid.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Although there are many things you should do to prepare your home for the market, there are also five home renovations you should avoid.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Biggest Mistakes Home Sellers Make</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-3-biggest-mistakes-home-sellers-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Sean Zanganeh</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-10 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Avoid+these+mistakes+when+selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It seems that home sellers keep making the same mistakes over and over in San Diego. We want you to be aware of these common mistakes so you avoid making them when it comes time to sell your home. Here are three big home selling mistakes to avoid:

1. Incorrect pricing. Price is very important in San Diego, and we notice that when consumers see a home priced accurately, they will not only pay more, but they will take action quicker. We want to sell your home for top dollar in the shortest amount of time, so we always recommend pricing at the market value for the best results.

2. Making your home hard to show. Some buyers may just be in town for a weekend or a few days and only have a limited time frame for when they can look at homes. We try to give our sellers as much advance notice as possible, but it’s also important that sellers be as flexible as they can while their home is on the market. A buyer might only have one opportunity to buy your home, so don’t send them away.

3. Lack of marketing exposure. Sometimes sellers want to just test the market or be a “secret seller.” However, if you’re actively trying to sell your home, you need exposure. You have to get your home out there online, get it seen, and continue to promote it to buyers in the area.

“Being a ‘secret seller’ won’t do you any good.”

If you have any questions for us or need some more advice for getting your home sold, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Avoid+these+mistakes+when+selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Sean+Zanganeh/Sean+Zanganeh++San+Diego%2C+CA+Real+Estate++Avoid+these+mistakes+when+selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are many mistakes that can be made during a home sale. Here are three of them you should avoid above all else.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Sean Zanganeh</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are many mistakes that can be made during a home sale. Here are three of them you should avoid above all else.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Francisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Sean Zanganeh</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Sean Zanganeh</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">As one of the top five agents with Windermere Homes & Estates, Sean Zanganeh prides himself on working closely with his clients in order to achieve their real estate goals. Sean uses proactive and innovative techniques to help you find your dream home. This podcast is just one way we work to help you make educated real estate decisions.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
